<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:35:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Omega Protocol (Ultimate)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi it’s Mr PB here to talk to you about some ideas to keep in mind that should help you safely progress on your beetle-killing journey. This is not a “max dps speedkill big parse” style document, this is a document containing ideas that can be implemented to ensure you’re safely meeting the required dps checks in each phase by allocating damage smartly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disclaimer: This is an in progress document, things may change retroactively as later parts of the fight are uncovered/planned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pandaemonium: Abyssos</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/pandaemonium-abyssos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/pandaemonium-abyssos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the encounter guide for the second tier of Endwalker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an important forewarning, allow me to repeat for the billionth time; Monk is a very flexible, very kill-time dependent job. What works at some times won’t work at others, so please don’t take the things contained herein as gospel to be replicated 100% of the time; you’ll still need to apply a little bit of brainpower to figure out what you want to be doing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pandaemonium: Asphodelos Encounter with Monk</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:46:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, Monks. Welcome to the encounter guide for the first tier of Endwalker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will review the different ways on what is possible to optimize from the entirety of the tier.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="erichtonios">Erichtonios&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nothing much to say, this is a dummy fight; do the optimal drift rotation for max damage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure you and the group are as central as possible during Intemperance One and Intemperance Two to ensure you’re going to hit everyone. If this still doesn’t work, you do have the following option, which consists of holding your Brotherhood (BH) if you aren’t sure to hit everyone and use it once you do the in/out mechanics. Note that if you hold it too long you may lose a use depending on the killtime.﻿&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>