<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Warrior on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/</link><description>Recent content in Warrior on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Warrior Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</guid><description>Universal Stat Priorities are:
Weapon Damage &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Main Stat &amp;raquo;&amp;raquo; Substats. Very few exceptions have existed before Endwalker. Warrior Substat priority and melds:
Crit &amp;gt; Comfy SkS &amp;gt; DH &amp;gt;= Det &amp;gt; TNC Be mindful of stat tiers when melding. Skill Speed
We don&amp;rsquo;t need it, but we might still want some. Mostly for comfy reasons such as fight phasing or oGCD lineups etc. oGCD lineups referring to situations where our GCD and oGCDs come up at the same time, forcing us to delay one or the other.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What is the BiS for Ultimates? UCoB / UWU / TEA ? Sets are currently being gathered in one doc: http://bit.ly/WARultimateBIS
Many pieces of gear are BiS when synced down.
The &amp;rsquo;low&amp;rsquo; stat on the higher ilvl gear will reach the stat cap on the lower ilvl gear.
This outweighs the melds you lose in some cases, and in others it is few points of stats behind.
UCoB: ilvl 418 and above will have both stats capped UWU: ilvl 470 and above will have both stats capped TEA: No available ilvl cap yet, syncing gear will not cap all substats and will ignore melding slots.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</guid><description>The Optimization Warrior Optimization focuses on manipulating the Surging Tempest buff refreshes, and “Carrying buffs” such as Nascent Chaos and Primal Rend Ready.
There’s the case of pushing out “3 IC Pot” windows and other rotational niches, but also disrespecting various mechanics by zeroing out the damage, or canceling a knockback with our Onslaught. Also, if you want a high percentile in FFLogs, you&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of a good kill time and Crit RNG.</description></item><item><title>Warrior FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:08:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</guid><description>Lvl70: Single Target vs AoE (Two Targets)?
TL;DR: Very equal, but lvl70 ST wins by a small margin
How do I relic?
Cap Crit, cap Det Check if you can replace any SkS melds in your gear with Det Get any missing SkS through relic Fill the rest of the relic with TNC How do I Upheaval?
All the time. I&amp;rsquo;m using Inner Release&amp;rsquo;s recast timer as a visual guide whether to hit Upheaval or not.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</guid><description>Warrior Openers and Rotation Warriors prepare their burst while waiting for the party buffs to appear.
After the buffs are up, the skills are used more or less in order of importance, as to gain potential re-uses towards the end of the fight.
Opener Optimization Assumed Timings:
Tomahawk starts at -0.70s and the pull starts at 0.00s Party buffs are expected to be up at around 7.80s Skill Speed requirements</description></item><item><title>Warrior Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:07:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</guid><description>Warrior Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heavy Swing HS 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 200. Maim 4 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 300. Increases Beast Gauge by 10.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:06:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</guid><description>Final Fantasy 14: Endwalker guide for Warrior By Mox Xinmagar &amp;amp; The Happy Team of Warriors
@Balance Discord
Intro Hello team! There should be an intro here, but I am bad at writing those.
Therefore I shall skip the funny talks about the Angriest Healer of FFXIV and let the rest of the guide do the talking.
This intro is focused on Lvl90 Endwalker Warrior. Please get to level 90 soon.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:06:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Henlo team!
We heard you needed some pointers on how to play WAR while leveling. The splits below are done based on what skills you unlock, and what you should take into account.
Do your job quests every five levels. Upgrade your gear every two to five levels. Remember your role actions. Gear We want Strength and Vitality. And Weapon Damage. Lots of Weapon Damage. The marketboard is a good place to pick up some cheap upgrades fast, along with Dungeon/Quest/Tomestone gear.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>