<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FFXIV on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/ffxiv/</link><description>Recent content in FFXIV on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/ffxiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machinist Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Machinist Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 21:52:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Machinist Guide Welcome to the Basic Machinist Guide! Within this document, you&amp;rsquo;ll find all the information you&amp;rsquo;ll need to play the job well. The links below can be used as teleports to other pages if you need the information while learning the job. Any questions can be directed to the Machinist channels in our Discord.
Openers
Advanced Guide
Video Guide
Gearing and Meld Priority
Skills Overview
Frequently Asked Questions</description></item><item><title>Machinist Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</guid><description>Openers With the addition of the extra tools, and despite the fact that we want to optimize as best as we can into buffs, it is still ideal to start off with a prepull Reassemble. It shaves off quite a bit of time to get the cooldown rolling and could possibly net us an extra usage depending on the fight layout in Dawntrail. Depending on the fight, we can transpose Drill and Air Anchor in the opener if we can gain an extra Drill for it.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended to give the reader the tools needed to approach encounter optimization as a Machinist. It assumes you are already familiar with the fundamentals of the job – if you need a refresher, please read the Basic Guide and come back when you&amp;rsquo;re done.
Introduction to Optimization This section will introduce some core concepts for optimizing encounters in FFXIV. If you are already familiar with optimization on other jobs, you can feel free to skip ahead!</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>6.X Red Mage Advanced Optimization Guide This guide will cover some Endwalker Red Mage optimization concepts and principles that aren’t fully covered in the basic job guide. The intended audience includes:
Red Mage players who have the fundamentals mostly down and are familiar with all the concepts in the basic job guide, but are trying to improve. High performing Red Mage players who get good logs through good GCD uptime, intuitive sense and repetition but wish to augment their theoretical understanding.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</guid><description>by Io Whitespirit (Faerie)
FOREWORD One of the biggest requests I have had is a more concise document on what people “need to know” before jumping into more difficult content. This is not meant to be a replacement for a general guide to Dancer; please see Ringabel’s extensive write-up instead, which will be linked at the end of the document in the appendix.
This guide will be broken down into three sections: Basics, Intermediate, and Advanced.</description></item><item><title>Dancer FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</guid><description>DANCE PARTNER PRIORITY This list is made in a gear/skill vacuum. This is the recommended partner priority list.
Special Note: some fights may favor certain Dance Partners over others based on phases/mechanics or ability to hit multiple targets.
Updated: January 19, 2021 to account for balance changes in patch 5.4.
SAM NIN MNK / BLM (crit build)* DRG / SMN RDM MCH BRD DNC *Data on BLM SpS build as a dance partner is not available due to length in time to reach BiS with this build as of this update, but value as a dance partner is believed to drop significantly between the two builds due to under utilization of Devilment.</description></item></channel></rss>