<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reaper on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/reaper/</link><description>Recent content in Reaper on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:45:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/reaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reaper Non-Standard Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</guid><description>Placeholder Test page.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:39:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is targeted at players looking to play and understand Reaper as they level up. It will cover some basic priorities for each level tier and will also serve as a priority list for playing Reaper at lower levels (for ultimates and such). If you are level 90 and looking to explore other guides please visit the following links:
Basic Guide
Advanced Guide
Skill Details
How to Unlock To unlock Reaper, you must first have these prerequisites met:</description></item><item><title>Reaper Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:34:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Reaper Guide Welcome to the Basic Guide for Reaper, which will cover everything you need to know to get started with becoming a Reaper! Included are an overview of the job’s playstyle, basic priority, abilities and core concepts.
Whether you’re a fresh level 90, a returning player, or just need a refresh, this guide will give you the tools you need to feel comfortable playing Reaper.
This guide is intended to be relatively basic and doesn’t go into huge explanations of specific situations or small nuances.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Reaper Advanced Rotational Theory Contributors: Dook Prime, Torael Valdis, Rin Karigani, Laille Ormesaing, Shalfu Nyan. Special thanks to Moth Kira and Jackal for the infographs! rDPS vs. aDPS and Reaper I wanted to start this guide off with talking about the FFLogs metrics and how they relate to Reaper, as well as how they can and should be used to measure performance. Currently, as it stands, FFLogs has three main metrics it measures DPS with:</description></item></channel></rss>