<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asphodelos: The Fourth Circle (Savage) Phase Two</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p4s-p2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 19:14:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p4s-p2/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating Hesperos&amp;rsquo;s second form in Asphodelos: The Fourth Circle (Savage).
The Fourth Circle (Savage) is the fourth raid encounter in the Pandaemonium series, available January 4, 2022 in Patch 6.05. Players must have completed the Quest &amp;ldquo;Who Wards the Warders?&amp;rdquo; and talk to Nemjiji in Labyrinthos (X:8.4, Y:27.4). Players must be item level 580 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos: The Fourth Circle (Savage) Phase One</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p4s-p1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 01:40:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p4s-p1/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating Hesperos&amp;rsquo;s first form in Asphodelos: The Fourth Circle (Savage).
The Fourth Circle (Savage) is the fourth raid encounter in the Pandaemonium series, available January 4, 2022 in Patch 6.05. Players must have completed the Quest &amp;ldquo;Who Wards the Warders?&amp;rdquo; and talk to Nemjiji in Labyrinthos (X:8.4, Y:27.4). Players must be item level 580 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos: The Third Circle (Savage)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p3s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 17:50:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p3s/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating the Phoinix in Asphodelos: The Third Circle (Savage).
The Third Circle (Savage) is the third raid encounter in the Pandaemonium series, available January 4, 2022 in Patch 6.05. Players must have completed the Quest &amp;ldquo;Who Wards the Warders?&amp;rdquo; and talk to Nemjiji in Labyrinthos (X:8.4, Y:27.4). Players must be item level 580 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.</description></item><item><title>Storm's Crown (Extreme)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/extreme/ex4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 23:46:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/extreme/ex4/</guid><description>This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating Barbariccia in Storm&amp;rsquo;s Crown (Extreme).
Barbariccia is the first trial encounter in the Buried Memory main scenario questline, available August 23, 2022 in Patch 6.2. Players must have completed the Main Scenario Quest “The Wind Rises” to unlock this duty. Players must be item level 600 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.
Loot Equipment:
Random i615 Windswept Weapon Windswept Weapon Coffer</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos: The Second Circle (Savage)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p2s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 20:20:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p2s/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating the Hippokampos in Asphodelos: The Second Circle (Savage).
The Second Circle (Savage) is the first raid encounter in the Pandaemonium series, available January 4, 2022 in Patch 6.05. Players must have completed the Quest &amp;ldquo;Who Wards the Warders?&amp;rdquo; and talk to Nemjiji in Labyrinthos (X:8.4, Y:27.4). Players must be item level 580 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos: The First Circle (Savage)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p1s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 17:28:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/encounters/savage/pandaemonium/p1s/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide tips and strategies for defeating Erichthonios in Asphodelos: The First Circle (Savage).
The First Circle (Savage) is the first raid encounter in the Pandaemonium series, available January 4, 2022 in Patch 6.05. Players must have completed the Quest &amp;ldquo;Who Wards the Warders?&amp;rdquo; and talk to Nemjiji in Labyrinthos (X:8.4, Y:27.4). Players must be item level 580 or above to challenge this fight in a non-premade group.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:16:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dark Knight Best In Slot Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS sets will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on what gear is available to you. Prioritizing item level over substats is generally recommended while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Paladin Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 07:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Post-6.3 rework, there is very little to optimize outside of rolling your GCD, keeping oGCDs on cooldown, and not dropping resources (Divine Might, Sword Oath stacks).
Encounter-specific optimizations can be discussed in the PLD Encounter forum in the Balance Discord.</description></item><item><title>Paladin Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 07:27:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Paladin Best in Slot Gear Priority and Pre-BiS Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on personal loot availability. Prioritizing item level over substats is encouraged while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Warrior fight tips</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:24:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>Quick and dirty notes for non-speedrunners.
P1S:
Nothing special. Full uptime fight.
Holmgang big busters 1 and 4. P2S:
-9s Prepull IR might be a gain.
However, it is possible to do a basic IC IR IC opener, and keep IR on cooldown while managing mechanics. Yes, you can use IR before Limit Cut happens. You&amp;rsquo;ll get 2-3 IR FCs out. If you only got two IR FCs out, the third one will stay ready until the boss is back again.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/stat-priority/</guid><description>Universal Stat Priorities are:
Weapon Damage &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Main Stat &amp;raquo;&amp;raquo; Substats. Very few exceptions have existed before Endwalker. Warrior Substat priority and melds:
Crit &amp;gt; Comfy SkS &amp;gt; DH &amp;gt;= Det &amp;gt; TNC Be mindful of stat tiers when melding. Skill Speed
We don&amp;rsquo;t need it, but we might still want some. Mostly for comfy reasons such as fight phasing or oGCD lineups etc. oGCD lineups referring to situations where our GCD and oGCDs come up at the same time, forcing us to delay one or the other.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What is the BiS for Ultimates? UCoB / UWU / TEA ? Sets are currently being gathered in one doc: http://bit.ly/WARultimateBIS
Many pieces of gear are BiS when synced down.
The &amp;rsquo;low&amp;rsquo; stat on the higher ilvl gear will reach the stat cap on the lower ilvl gear.
This outweighs the melds you lose in some cases, and in others it is few points of stats behind.
UCoB: ilvl 418 and above will have both stats capped UWU: ilvl 470 and above will have both stats capped TEA: No available ilvl cap yet, syncing gear will not cap all substats and will ignore melding slots.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:09:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/advanced-guide/</guid><description>The Optimization Warrior Optimization focuses on manipulating the Surging Tempest buff refreshes, and “Carrying buffs” such as Nascent Chaos and Primal Rend Ready.
There’s the case of pushing out “3 IC Pot” windows and other rotational niches, but also disrespecting various mechanics by zeroing out the damage, or canceling a knockback with our Onslaught. Also, if you want a high percentile in FFLogs, you&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of a good kill time and Crit RNG.</description></item><item><title>Warrior FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:08:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/faq/</guid><description>Lvl70: Single Target vs AoE (Two Targets)?
TL;DR: Very equal, but lvl70 ST wins by a small margin
How do I relic?
Cap Crit, cap Det Check if you can replace any SkS melds in your gear with Det Get any missing SkS through relic Fill the rest of the relic with TNC How do I Upheaval?
All the time. I&amp;rsquo;m using Inner Release&amp;rsquo;s recast timer as a visual guide whether to hit Upheaval or not.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/openers/</guid><description>Warrior Openers and Rotation Warriors prepare their burst while waiting for the party buffs to appear.
After the buffs are up, the skills are used more or less in order of importance, as to gain potential re-uses towards the end of the fight.
Opener Optimization Assumed Timings:
Tomahawk starts at -0.70s and the pull starts at 0.00s Party buffs are expected to be up at around 7.80s Skill Speed requirements</description></item><item><title>Warrior Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:07:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/skills-overview/</guid><description>Warrior Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heavy Swing HS 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 200. Maim 4 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 300. Increases Beast Gauge by 10.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:06:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/basic-guide/</guid><description>Final Fantasy 14: Endwalker guide for Warrior By Mox Xinmagar &amp;amp; The Happy Team of Warriors
@Balance Discord
Intro Hello team! There should be an intro here, but I am bad at writing those.
Therefore I shall skip the funny talks about the Angriest Healer of FFXIV and let the rest of the guide do the talking.
This intro is focused on Lvl90 Endwalker Warrior. Please get to level 90 soon.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:06:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Henlo team!
We heard you needed some pointers on how to play WAR while leveling. The splits below are done based on what skills you unlock, and what you should take into account.
Do your job quests every five levels. Upgrade your gear every two to five levels. Remember your role actions. Gear We want Strength and Vitality. And Weapon Damage. Lots of Weapon Damage. The marketboard is a good place to pick up some cheap upgrades fast, along with Dungeon/Quest/Tomestone gear.</description></item><item><title>Warrior Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/warrior/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dancer Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 12:05:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Best-in-Slot (BiS) / Itemization Best-in-slot New BiS (5.55) with iLvl 535 Relic Weapon Old BiS (5.4) with Edenmorn Weapon - (watch melds)
BiS Food: Smoked Chicken
BiS Potion: Grade 4 Tincture of Dexterity
Meld Priority Crit &amp;gt; DH &amp;gt; DET
Gearing Up Guide Guide to gearing DNC (5.58) - includes starting gear and tomestone buy order
Best starting gearset before accessing any weekly savage gear pieces or spending Tomestones of Revelation: view this Starting Gearset on Etro.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Best-in-Slot</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 06:11:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samurai Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 05:02:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/stat-priority/</guid><description>Based on current gear available to us, if you&amp;rsquo;re not using the Gear Planner to figure out what melds are best for your specific situation the below is a decent blind meld order to follow: SKS (to tier)* &amp;gt; Crit &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt;= DH
Check out the Gear Planner here.
*To one of the recommended SkS ranges.\
Viable GCD/SkS ranges (with Shifu counted) for looping:\
Recast with Shifu SkS Range Filler Req.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:35:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/basic-guide/</guid><description>Foreword With the release of Endwalker, Samurai is now celebrating four years in the game. With Boxer’s permission I am updating this guide for Endwalker. 6.0 doesn’t change a whole lot about the fundamentals of playing Samurai or melee 6.1 has fundamentally changed the way Samurai plays in Endwalker, and the changes will be covered in this document. Despite this, this guide is still intended for newer players.
-Zombii
The following section summarizes Samurai’s abilities.</description></item><item><title>Samurai FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:35:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/faq/</guid><description>Is X better than Y for me?
For weapons: item level (ilvl)/weapon damage (wd) wins, regardless of substats. For armor: ilvl usually wins, unless 5 materia slots. For same-ilvl pieces: substat itemization can be in your favor or not depending on the rest of your gear and stat tiering. When in doubt, use the Gear Planner - only here can you get an accurate answer for your setup!
Samurai has positionals?</description></item><item><title>Samurai Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:34:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samurai Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:34:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/openers/</guid><description>Your standard opener which will be used in the majority of encounters. Due to phasing, in some instances it may be best to begin with Kasha into Gekko instead.
If Iai weaves are easier than double weaves for you, feel free to move Senei forward before Kaeshi: Setsugekka.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:34:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/skills-overview/</guid><description>Samurai Skills Overview Global Cooldown Actions (Single Target) Icon Name Description Hakaze Single target combo starter. 200 potency. +5 Kenki. Jinpu Single target second step combo. 120 potency, 280 potency if combo from Hakaze. Combo Bonus: Fugetsu buff (increased damage dealt by 13% for 40s), +5 Kenki. Shifu Single target second step combo. 120 potency, 280 potency if combo from Hakaze. Combo Bonus: Fuka buff (reduces GCD and autoattack delay by 13%) for 40s, +5 Kenki.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:33:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Level 50 Level 50 Opener
Rotate through your combos and smash that Midare button. Use Meikyo for Gekko and Kasha past the opener. Refresh Higanbana as close to 0 as possible.
Level 52 Introduces Kenki Gauge and Hissatsu: Shinten. Use it when you want and be sure not to overcap.
Level 60 Level 60 Opener
Once you begin accruing Kenki to spend on Shinten, the opener should look like this.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Samurai Savage Best In Slot: 2.14 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,201 DPS] Etro
2.14 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;slowSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,029 DPS] Etro
28 GCD loop, two filler GCDs, most used sets. Play these.
2.07 GCD Relic &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [23,102 DPS] Etro
2.07 GCD OLD &amp;lsquo;flexSam&amp;rsquo; BiS - [22,933 DPS] Etro
29 GCD loop, three filler GCDs, beginner friendly due to Gekko/Kasha filler, can only iai-weave on ping ≤ 10ms without clipping.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:54:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended for the casual player looking for advice on how to play Scholar in leveling dungeons. Below, we’ll briefly describe all Scholar actions, grouped by level, and some general guidelines for when to use them. For more detailed ability descriptions, please consult the in-game tooltips or job guide, and if you’d like to learn more about playing and optimizing Scholar, check out our other guides.
Quick Glossary SCH: Scholar CD (Cooldown): The time it takes before you’re able to cast an action again.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended for players who are looking to play Scholar in level 90 trials and raids. For information about playing Scholar while leveling, please see our Leveling Guide.
Quick Glossary SCH: Scholar CD (Cooldown): The time it takes before you’re able to cast an action again. GCD (Global Cooldown): Spells that share the same base recast time. On SCH, these are mostly spells with about 2.5s recast time, plus Resurrection.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:53:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes Broil IV cast time is reduced to 1.5s base cast time. You can weave one oGCD after it without clipping. Do not use Ruin II for weaving. New skills: Protraction and Expedient Shields apply at the slidecast window. It is now possible to cast Adloquium and immediately use Deployment Tactics, but this is still not recommended because this will clip GCD. Energy Drain no longer restores MP. Aetherflow MP is increased but this is a net loss for players who averaged 3+ Energy Drains per minute (including Energy Drains from Dissipation).</description></item><item><title>Scholar Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</guid><description>Remember that the exact ability usage in these openers is not strict. If you need to use a heal in the opener or hold an AF stack for later healing do so. This is the ability usage you&amp;rsquo;d do on a dummy, but not every fight allows for it.
Chain Stratagem is varied, there are several factors that impact its usage within a raid setting. Usually, it is dependent on composition, but may also need to be adjusted for fight timings, though these situations are fairly rare.</description></item><item><title>Scholar FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</guid><description>Scholar FAQ How can I see my fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate in battle?
A. Character Configuration &amp;gt; Control Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Target&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Target Settings&amp;rdquo;, Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Disable targeting of pets and minions when in battle.&amp;rdquo;
B. Character Config &amp;gt; Display Name Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Own&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Pets&amp;rdquo; set &amp;ldquo;Display Name Settings&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Always&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;During Battle&amp;rdquo;
Both options must be set this way or your fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate will be hidden.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</guid><description>Consider melding Det over DH for prog, as the damage benefits are basically equal on average. Meld SpS to a comfy tier if you wish, low priority during prog.
Piety is a binary stat, as any more than you needed to not run out of mp was wasted stats. Because of this, when choosing our substats, avoiding excess Piety is the best way for us to increase our damage, and you&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes see our low piety sets use lower iLvl equipment to avoid Piety (this is still the exception rather than the rule, don&amp;rsquo;t actively use lower iLvl items to dodge Piety without calculating out the gain yourself).</description></item><item><title>Paladin Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:07:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paladin Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:06:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/openers/</guid><description>Paladin Openers Tanks currently use Grade 8 Tinctures of Strength (Strength also affects tank magic potency, including healing).
In-depth Opener and Rotation Graphic</description></item><item><title>Paladin Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/skills-overview/</guid><description>Buffs Iron Will Toggle | 3s cooldown after toggling on. | 1s cooldown after toggling off.
Increases enmity generation by 10x (Enmity is also known as aggro, hate, etc.).
Keep this on in dungeons or as the main tank (in content with more than one tank).
Fight or Flight 60s cooldown.
+25% damage dealt for 20 seconds.
Requiescat 60s cooldown.
320 potency.
Provides 4 stacks of Requiescat, granting instant casts and increasing the potency of Holy Spirit, Holy Circle, Confiteor, and the Blade of Valor combo actions.</description></item><item><title>Paladin Basics Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</guid><description>Welcome to the Basics Guide for Paladin! Whether you are a fresh level 90, a returning player, or just need a refresher, this guide will get you started and allow you to hit the ground running.
Since this is a basic introduction to level 90 Paladin, this guide will not go into many nuances and topics that are tied to high-end optimization. If you are looking for such information, you may find it in one of the dedicated guides below:</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 02:21:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Red Mage Skill Overview All skills are listed with their level 90 effects and potencies. Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Jolt II A 320 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases both Black and White Mana by 2. Verthunder III A 380 potency Spell with a cast time of five seconds that increases Black Mana by 6. Has a 50% chance to proc Verfire Ready. Verfire A 340 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases Black Mana by 5.</description></item><item><title>Bard Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 03:15:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5x Best In Slot BiS with Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/8418d22e-d70e-4b1a-87e0-d2b79dc3bd91
BiS, no Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/865fc886-994f-4c28-8fc1-4379f160a916
2.50 BiS for high ping (relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/6e8892d6-68b0-4597-ba17-1efdc0e62084
2.50s BiS for high ping (no relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/cac58997-d0d5-4e92-b6fd-a131e8a775e2
TEA Best In Slot: Relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/1081f33f-8c37-4ef4-b569-30e30092174f
Relic 2.47s: https://etro.gg/gearset/f0eafbaf-fb74-48ee-99a8-21780ff8a793
(These are basically equal, pick to taste.)
No-relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/c4e0a8ce-e69e-4efc-8971-f4ae5d4c5918
For level 70 Ultimates: Any gear that&amp;rsquo;s i470 or higher will suffice, as it syncs down to maximum substats for UWU. You can get some bonus value out of a 515/535 relic by keeping its substats at 318/280 or less (for UWU/UCoB).</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 17:06:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dragoon Best-in-Slot Lists 5.55 Best-in-Slot Gearsets 2.50 GCD (Raid Chest) - http://bit.ly/drg250raid
2.50 GCD (Tome Chest) - https://bit.ly/drg250tome Slight downgrade if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to get the E12S chest.
2.46 GCD - http://bit.ly/drg246bis
5.55 Best-in-Slot, no Relic 2.50 GCD - https://etro.gg/gearset/7f0557b6-d86f-4d3a-8953-4db56bd23488
2.46 GCD - https://etro.gg/gearset/bc44395f-4ce1-47aa-b52a-7bcbcb90d152
Ultimates Best-in-Slot Discussion If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to do one of the level 70 Ultimate encounters, you should just sync down current gear. If you wear anything with an Item Level higher than 418 for UCoB or 470 for UWU, you will maximize the two stats on the gear.</description></item><item><title>The Weapon's Refrain (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-weapons-refrain-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-weapons-refrain-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>General Fight Tips Managing Resources Due to damage scaling in Endwalker, push timings in The Weapon’s Refrain can vary greatly, between groups and even between pulls in the same group. Therefore, you should use this guide for a general idea of how to manage each phase, but keep in mind this may not always work for you, and you should aim to find a timeline that works for you during progression.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended to give the reader the tools needed to approach encounter optimization as a Machinist. It assumes you are already familiar with the fundamentals of the job – if you need a refresher, please read the Basic Guide and come back when you&amp;rsquo;re done.
Introduction to Optimization This section will introduce some core concepts for optimizing encounters in FFXIV. If you are already familiar with optimization on other jobs, you can feel free to skip ahead!</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:47:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description>BiS: &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS Tier (Relic)&amp;rdquo;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/1c64d9a9-892b-48a8-b7d1-f760839d659c
&amp;ldquo;Crit 2030 SPS Tier (Relic)&amp;rdquo;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/b470c4c6-6f4a-47c8-8162-52ac09494e02
&amp;ldquo;SMN/RDM-Friendly BiS&amp;rdquo;: (can use the SMN/RDM BiS without swapping melds)
Use the &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS&amp;rdquo; Tier set for BLM, and use SMN/RDM BiS on the other casters. Shared pieces between the sets have no meld conflicts.
Thanks to incoherent#0649 for the provided relic sets!
Please see http://bit.ly/BLMGear for additional sets, including non-relic BiS sets
&amp;ldquo;TEA BiS&amp;rdquo;: (Please look at the sheet below under &amp;ldquo;Patch 5.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Non-Standard Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</guid><description>Placeholder Test page.</description></item><item><title>Sage Best in Slot</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:49:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Omega Protocol (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 04:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</guid><description>The Omega Protocol (Ultimate) RDM Guide This raid features a unique mix of multiple tight DPS checks, movement-intensive mechanics requiring real-time adjustment, and flexible optimization potential. That said, with some planning and smart resource management, Red Mage is able to perform well in this raid and bring a lot of value to a party.
There are six phases in this raid. Generally, every phase has a DPS check that requires some basic optimization, but the difficulty of Phase 2 and Phase 3 DPS checks tend to depend on party composition and buff timings, with Phase 2 benefitting cleave-heavy compositions and Phase 3 benefitting full uptime 2-minute burst compositions.</description></item><item><title>SCH UCOB fight tips</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-ucob-fight-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-ucob-fight-tips/</guid><description>Introduction This document contains suggestions on how to use your cooldowns effectively and small things you can do to maximize them. Ideally, you should communicate with your Co-Healer to make a plan that reduces stress for both of you and maximizes damage between you while being safe.
The Unending Coil of Bahamut (uCOB) Gearing For level 70 Ultimates and Healers, we can mostly get away with using all synced gear with at least ilevel 470.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 07:49:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Astrologian Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 07:33:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5 AST BiS SETS https://bit.ly/astgearcalc
So we&amp;rsquo;re here, finally with a proper writeup.
Making BiS was expected to be very difficult this tier with AST&amp;rsquo;s new affinity for SpS&amp;hellip;but instead it actually was quite easy. Avoid Piety like the plague and there you go, there&amp;rsquo;s your BiS pieces.
Higher Piety sets also have the nice consolation of having a wealth of Crit (rather than the traditional disgusting amounts of Det) so it won&amp;rsquo;t even feel that bad to swap to lower damage for the sake of Piety.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:37:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>6.X Red Mage Advanced Optimization Guide This guide will cover some Endwalker Red Mage optimization concepts and principles that aren’t fully covered in the basic job guide. The intended audience includes:
Red Mage players who have the fundamentals mostly down and are familiar with all the concepts in the basic job guide, but are trying to improve. High performing Red Mage players who get good logs through good GCD uptime, intuitive sense and repetition but wish to augment their theoretical understanding.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:35:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/openers/</guid><description>Full Size
Why do we cast Verthunder twice?
Casting Verthunder twice is intentional as it allows us to guarantee a proc from Verholy as we will have lower white mana when we use it, resulting in us having both procs after our melee combo. You can also do this in the reverse order, casting Veraero twice and then Verflare.
Why are we potting a GCD later than usual?
Potting after the 2nd GCD allows us to use both Swiftcast and Acceleration after the first GCD, beginning the cooldown of both of those abilities and allowing us to comfortably weave our potion, Manafication, and Embolden in the next 2 GCDs.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Red Mage Level 90 Guide for 6.x Overview This guide will cover changes to Red Mage and proper rotations and ability usage in the Endwalker expansion. While the core foundation of Red Mage has not changed at all since its introduction in Stormblood, many smaller changes and quality of life improvements made in Endwalker have changed how we approach different aspects of the job, all of which will be covered below.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Red Mage Leveling Guide for 6.x Introduction The purpose of this guide is to assist players new to either Red Mage, or to the game entirely in learning how to properly play both their job and their role as they level up to 90. It will be split into sections for different level ranges that cover new abilities gained at these levels, as well as covering other basic concepts that will assist players in playing Red Mage.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide a basic overview of White Mage and offer guidelines on how to use each skill in its toolkit effectively in any environment. As healers do not have a strict healing rotation, this guide will focus on highlighting what makes each skill unique and explain some common use cases.
White Mage is considered by many people to be the most beginner friendly healer, and rightfully so.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:47:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide was written by Akashi for players who are seeking to, or are currently leveling Ninja. The guide aims to inform players about how to initially play as Ninja, what gear they should use while they level and where to find it, the key basics of the job, as well as some example openers for lower levels. If you are already a level 90 Ninja and are looking for information pertaining to the job at level 90, please see the Basic Ninja Guide.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Skill Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:45:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single-Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Slice - 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 320. Generates 10 Soul. Waxing Slice - 5 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 400. Generates 10 Soul. Infernal Slice - 30 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The third action in your main combo.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/skills-overview/</guid><description>Weaponskills (Commonly referred to as GCDs) Spinning Edge
Delivers an attack with a potency of 220. Grants 5 Ninki. This is the first part of our basic combo.
Gust Slash
Delivers an attack with a potency of 160. If used after Spinning Edge in the combo, it will instead deliver an attack with a potency of 320. Grants 5 Ninki if used in the combo. This is the second part of our basic combo.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:39:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is targeted at players looking to play and understand Reaper as they level up. It will cover some basic priorities for each level tier and will also serve as a priority list for playing Reaper at lower levels (for ultimates and such). If you are level 90 and looking to explore other guides please visit the following links:
Basic Guide
Advanced Guide
Skill Details
How to Unlock To unlock Reaper, you must first have these prerequisites met:</description></item><item><title>Sage Skills</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:38:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Before you Start: Eukrasia First, a note about skills with &amp;ldquo;Eukrasian&amp;rdquo; in the name. These are upgraded versions of other skills that you would access by using the &amp;ldquo;Eukrasia&amp;rdquo; skill first. For example, to cast Eukrasian Dosis, first cast Eukrasia, then cast Dosis. Eukrasia itself is a 1-second, instant cast Global Cooldown (GCD) and the buffed ability will become a 1.5-second, instant-cast GCD. Neither of these cast times are affected by spell speed, so any Eukrasian GCD will always be 2.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:34:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Reaper Guide Welcome to the Basic Guide for Reaper, which will cover everything you need to know to get started with becoming a Reaper! Included are an overview of the job’s playstyle, basic priority, abilities and core concepts.
Whether you’re a fresh level 90, a returning player, or just need a refresh, this guide will give you the tools you need to feel comfortable playing Reaper.
This guide is intended to be relatively basic and doesn’t go into huge explanations of specific situations or small nuances.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:34:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide will cover Summoner changes, rotations and ability usage in the Endwalker expansion. The core foundation of Summoner has changed significantly, most notably with the complete removal of damage over time abilities (dots) and the newly added primal arcanum system (gems). The basic flow and idea of Summoner’s rotation can be simplified as follows:
Use Searing Light in alignment with party raid buffs Summon Bahamut and use all abilities to refresh your primal gems Go through three primal phases Summon Phoenix and use all abilities to refresh your primal gems Go through three primal phases Repeat Within that framework, there is additional nuance such as optimizing damage into raid buffs, moving certain spells around based on movement requirements, and making effective use of Summoner’s various utility tools.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:33:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ninja Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/basic-guide/</guid><description>If you have any questions, feel free to ask in the #nin_questions channel.
Overview Ninja is a fast-paced yet flexible job with a high focus on a powerful burst every one and two minutes. It is unique from other jobs with its utilization of Ninjutsus, a combo-like system that allows a Ninja to form a multitude of ranged attacks. We have a personal buff every minute (Trick Attack) where we emphasize landing all of our biggest attacks within 15.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/openers/</guid><description>Fast Enshroud Opener Full Size
Soul Sow pre-pull
Cast Harpe after 2 appears on the countdown
Shadow of Death
Arcane Circle as fast possible Soul Slice
Soul Slice
Potion here if you are using potion in the opener Plentiful Harvest
This will clip if your GCD is faster than 2.47, or you have high ping. If the clip here is bothersome, or over a quarter of your GCD cast, use the Early Gluttony opener.</description></item><item><title>Monk Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Monk Guide Welcome to the basic guide for Monk, which will cover all of the information necessary to get you off your feet and onto your hands while you kick some voidsent in the face. Included is a look into the various systems that come together to define the Monk playstyle, suggested openers, and explanations on how to correctly form burst windows. If your thirst for knowledge remains unsated once you reach the conclusion of this guide, head on over to the Advanced guide where we will dive further into the depths of forbidden Monk information.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/openers/</guid><description>⦿ Late weave Trick Attack as much as possible without clipping. ⦿ Mug should be held a GCD after the opener (at next usage) then used strictly on cooldown after.
⦿ It is important to start preparing the Suiton prepull at -6 seconds on the countdown and use at -1 second. This will not pull the boss early and allows future mudras to come off cooldown sooner.
⦿ This version uses Trick Attack at the 4th GCD instead of the standard 3rd.</description></item><item><title>Monk Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single Target GCDs Monk has six core single-target GCDs:
Bootshine has a potency of 210, or 310 when you have Leaden Fist. When in Opo-Opo form, Bootshine will always crit. Dragon Kick has a potency of 320. When in Opo-Opo form, it will grant the Leaden Fist buff. True Strike has a potency of 300. It can only be executed from Raptor form. Twin Snakes has a potency of 280. It also grants a 15% damage increase buff, Disciplined Fist, that lasts for 15 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 18:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/stat-priority/</guid><description>Highest iLvl gear available generally will be the best option, regardless of substats, thanks to an increase in Dexterity and Weapon Damage. Between items of the same iLvl, the stat priority is Crit &amp;gt; DET &amp;gt; DH &amp;raquo;&amp;raquo; SkS.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 18:06:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ninja FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 18:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions:
Q: Are there any Shukuchi macros?
A: Yes, the main ones use either to go to your target at the time, or use &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, etc to go to specific party members.
Q: Why does our BiS not follow the stat priority?
A: Because of stat tiering and how it works together with our rotation, our rotation simulation brought out this exact combination of materia to be a higher average DPS value than fully following our stat priority.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Job Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 18:05:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ninja Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 18:02:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Best-in-Slot (BiS) For your Best-in-Slot gear, you will generally be going for Weapon Damage&amp;gt; Dexterity&amp;gt; Crit&amp;gt; Direct Hit&amp;gt; Determination &amp;raquo; Skill Speed. This is not 100% exact once you get to the max gear, but until you have that, that is the priority in stats.
2.12 GCD BiS https://etro.gg/gearset/dec9811d-c02c-4378-b046-d3cebe42eccb
2.11 GCD BiS https://etro.gg/gearset/33b9d186-963a-4cdb-84a0-6b2ebbadc652
2.10 GCD BiS https://etro.gg/gearset/c1c01cbb-f99b-4ba8-bbe3-e9d03a76b280
Use the 2.12 GCD BiS for general play, the 2.11 plays around potential extra gcds and is more consistent at doing triple Bhavas in Tricks, which still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in every fight, and also requires a lower ping to work.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 14:01:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dragoon FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions Type !faq drg in #bot_spam for a full list of commands to answer other common questions!
How does Raiden Thrust work?
Raiden Thrust is an upgraded True Thrust. It combos into both Disembowel and Vorpal Thrust and replaces True Thrust on your bar when it’s ready. You activate it by successfully landing the positional on the fifth hit of your combo (Fang and Claw or Wheeling Thrust following Wheeling Thrust or Fang and Claw, respectively).</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/openers/</guid><description>Dragoon Opener and Rotation The primary use of the Opener is to prepare your cooldown alignment for the rest of the encounter. With our new job design, it’s possible that we’ll actually have fight-specific openers down the stretch.
Standard Opener Full size image
The backbone of ten GCDs in sequence will - in general - never be changed, but the two blocks of oGCDs (Buffs and Attacks) can be shuffled around within their respective slots if necessary to accommodate specific encounter timings.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:35:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/basic-guide/</guid><description>Saving The Dragoon Overview Dragoon is a relatively static melee DPS job with a high focus on weaving off-Global Cooldown (oGCD) actions between a rigid 10-hit sequence of Global Cooldown (GCD) actions. Burst windows can get hectic, and prioritizing the various skills you need to execute can become a rather significant hassle in some instances. Endwalker has doubled down on this by introducing the ability to utilize even more oGCD actions at regular intervals, as if we didn’t have enough already.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Dragoon Leveling Guide Gear Always use the highest Item Level gear available to you. The increase of Strength and survivability outweighs potentially more favorable substats in lower Item Level gear. The total amount of substats is also higher.
Dragoons use Maiming armor and Slaying accessories. Low level gear may not be labeled as such, so make sure you always equip gear that gives a bonus to Strength.
Know Your Role Melee DPS jobs have a unique mechanic in Positionals.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:25:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:24:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Written by Reina Kousaka of Leviathan Last updated: Feb 13 2022
Prologue “To make it short, they don&amp;rsquo;t teach or research &amp;ldquo;potency per second&amp;rdquo; in universities.” - DiaStarvy
Hello. I am Reina, a caster player, and I am standing on the shoulders of giants. This document aims to provide a comprehensive guide on advanced non-standard playstyle (also known as the AI rotation). There is the assumption you know all of the basics of BLM, including abbreviations and fundamentals.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:24:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</guid><description>Q: What is Umbral Soul used for? A: Purely a downtime tool, a better version of Transpose. Lets you build back up to Umbral Ice III + Three Umbral Hearts during downtime, so you can Thunder III -&amp;gt; Fire III when you can hit something again. If you end a fight in Astral Fire, Transpose into UI so you can use Umbral Soul. Do not use Umbral Soul during uptime.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:24:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</guid><description>Openers Openers should put abilities on cooldown, fit strong spells within buff windows, and minimize clipping. All openers assume there is a pull countdown and the boss is pulled at zero. If your group pulls earlier, adjust them as necessary. Use the highest tier Tincture / Infusion / Potion of Intelligence available.
With all openers being very close in estimated output over the course of the entire encounter, it is instead recommended to choose your opener based on your current spell speed, with consideration towards potential fight-specific requirements.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:23:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Blizzard 1 Spell 400 2.5s 2.5s Deals ice damage with a potency of 180. Fire 2 Spell 800 2.5s 2.5s Deals fire damage with a potency of 180. Transpose 4 Ability - Instant 5s Swaps Astral Fire with a single Umbral Ice or Umbral Ice with a single Astral Fire. Thunder 6 Spell 200 2.5s 2.5s Deals lightning damage with a potency of 30.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 20:23:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Single Target Leveling Rotation Sub Level 35 Fire I (F1) spam &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; Blizzard I (B1) until max MP &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; repeat
Refresh Thunder I (T1) as necessary.
Levels 35-59 Blizzard III (B3) &amp;gt; optional B1 for MP tick &amp;gt; Thunder III (T3)/T1 &amp;gt; Fire III (F3) &amp;gt; F1 spam until low MP &amp;gt; repeat
Use your Fire III proc (F3P) as you get them, but don&amp;rsquo;t cancel casts to use procs.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 19:51:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 19:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>6.x Standard BLM Guide By: Rika Vanih
Job Overview Black Mage is a caster specializing in high, steady personal damage in place of providing party buffs. The job maintains a cyclical flow of expending MP via long, powerful casts in Astral Fire then swapping to refresh MP in Umbral Ice. While the rotation itself is somewhat simple, utilizing its movement tools and the flexibility built into its rotation to their fullest is key to maintaining uptime and maximizing damage as a Black Mage.</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 13:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/basic-guide/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Rotation Guide Authors Krom Ulus | Adamantoise (Aether) | krom#7427
Azazel Raine | Balmung (Crystal) | Azazel#1000
Playstyle and Core Concepts Gunbreaker is a higher APM job with a focus on building and spending cartridges to deal very high damage inside of tight burst windows. This guide will introduce the relevant actions, gauge usage, and priority system to manage your rotation.
The rotation is a builder-spender rotation focused on maximizing damage inside the personal 20% damage buff, No Mercy, every 60 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 16:26:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/skills-overview/</guid><description>Dragoon Skills Overview Global Cooldown Actions (Single Target) All potencies assume level 90, meaning potency increases through traits are already included.
Icon Name Acronym Level Description True Thrust TT 1 Basic combo initiator for both the Chaos Thrust and the Full Thrust combo with 230 potency. Raiden Thrust RT 76 Direct upgrade to True Thrust after successfully landing the last combo action, i.e. Fang and Claw in the Chaos Thrust combo and Wheeling Thrust in the Full Thrust combo.</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 04:30:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/skills-overview/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Skills Overview Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Keen Edge The first skill of our basic combo. 200 potency. Brutal Shell Used after Keen Edge. 300 combo potency. Heals for 200 potency and gives a shield equal to the amount healed. Solid Barrel Used after Brutal Shell. 360 combo potency, Generates one cartridge. Burst Strike 380 potency attack that requires one cartridge. Grants Ready to Blast. Gnashing Fang 380 potency attack that requires one cartridge.</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 04:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 03:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 02:22:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 02:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/openers/</guid><description>Opener Your opener is flexible and No Mercy can be used earlier than what is listed in either of these openers if necessary to allow for additional uses to be used before phases or mechanics.
The Lightning Shot is not required in these, but is heavily suggested for engagement timing. Facepulling is not consistent unless you can pull from within melee range without beginning the encounter.
Standard Opener (≤ 2.47 GCD) Full Size</description></item><item><title>Paladin Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 01:19:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 01:14:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Gunbreaker Best in Slot 5.58 Best in Slot (BiS) Compendium: *Damage is within negligible variance. Choose the set that best suits your comfort level. Fight specific recommendations to come at a later date.
Savage Relic BiS 5.58 Relic i530 BiS 2.41 - 13,892.9 DPS 2.43 - 13,850.0 DPS Non-Relic BiS Food: Chicken Fettuccine
i530 2.41 - 13,808.7 DPS
Level 70 Ultimates Unending Coil of Bahamut (UCoB) BiS UCoB i515 Relic BiS The Weapon&amp;rsquo;s Refrain (UWU) BiS UWU i515 Relic BiS Level 80 Ultimates 5.</description></item><item><title>Paladin FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 01:14:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/faq/</guid><description>Why is Circle of Scorn used immediately in the opener?
Circle of Scorn is used before Fight or Flight in most openers and kept on cooldown in most phases for two reasons:
Its short cooldown (25 seconds) is equal to the duration of Fight or Flight, meaning one CoS usage should always occur during FoF regardless of their respective timings, given full uptime. Its high DoT uptime (~60%) means that any delays are likely to cost ticks at the end of the phase, resulting in a potency loss overall.</description></item><item><title>Monk Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 22:26:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What do I meld on gear generally? Critical Hit, then Direct Hit and Determination
The BiS skill speed is at the 761 speed tier, for reference for skill speed.
What&amp;rsquo;s the BiS? Etro link (802 Speed):
https://etro.gg/gearset/388e7ee7-2919-49bf-b1d8-75fcfae73ce5
If you have a Relic you have this marginally better list of gear (etro&amp;rsquo;d courtesy of StormGail):
https://etro.gg/gearset/2a0fbde0-fa6f-47b6-aa0d-9b7d240c6e19 ­
SkS Tiers/Substat Tiers http://theoryjerks.akhmorning.com/stats/
Use these tables of on this website if you want to see how close you are to reaching your next stat breakpoint or just to further understand your stats in general.</description></item><item><title>Monk Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 14:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Advanced Monk Gameplay Techniques: Reaching Enlightenment Opener Variations The two basic opener choices are not going to work perfectly in every situation. As such, we can modify our openers quite easily in order to better suit our needs.
Early Openers An early opener is exactly what it sounds like. By skipping past the Opo GCD straight into a Twin Snakes, we are able to get our buffs on cooldown sooner. These openers are generally used in situations where a phase or fight would end while we are still in a buff window in order to squeeze more effective usage out of those buffs.</description></item><item><title>Monk Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 14:15:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</guid><description>Openers Other Resources Rotation Looping rotation - French translation - Korean translation - Other Resources Videos:
Comprehensive Monk Video Guide Braindead Looping 6:30 dummy rotation Optimal Drift 6:30 dummy rotation Double Solar 6:30 dummy rotation 6:30 Double Solar dummy + explanation (French)</description></item><item><title>The Omega Protocol (Ultimate)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</guid><description>Hi it’s Mr PB here to talk to you about some ideas to keep in mind that should help you safely progress on your beetle-killing journey. This is not a “max dps speedkill big parse” style document, this is a document containing ideas that can be implemented to ensure you’re safely meeting the required dps checks in each phase by allocating damage smartly.
Disclaimer: This is an in progress document, things may change retroactively as later parts of the fight are uncovered/planned.</description></item><item><title>Pandaemonium: Abyssos</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/pandaemonium-abyssos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/pandaemonium-abyssos/</guid><description>Welcome to the encounter guide for the second tier of Endwalker.
As an important forewarning, allow me to repeat for the billionth time; Monk is a very flexible, very kill-time dependent job. What works at some times won’t work at others, so please don’t take the things contained herein as gospel to be replicated 100% of the time; you’ll still need to apply a little bit of brainpower to figure out what you want to be doing.</description></item><item><title>The Epic of Alexander (Ultimate) - TEA</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/fight-tips/the-epic-of-alexander-ultimate-tea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 08:39:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/fight-tips/the-epic-of-alexander-ultimate-tea/</guid><description>The Epic of Alexander (Ultimate) is the Ultimate released in Final Fantasy XIV: Shadowbringers. This encounter is split into 4 Phases: Living Liquid, Brute Justice &amp;amp; Cruise Chaser, Alexander Prime and Perfect Alexander. This guide will go over the Operners, rotations and provide tips for different push-timings and general oGCD usage. This guide assumes that you have a basic understanding of the class and its fundamentals.
Best in Slot Etro Link</description></item><item><title>Pandaemonium: Asphodelos Encounter with Monk</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:46:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>Hello, Monks. Welcome to the encounter guide for the first tier of Endwalker.
We will review the different ways on what is possible to optimize from the entirety of the tier.
Erichtonios Nothing much to say, this is a dummy fight; do the optimal drift rotation for max damage.
Make sure you and the group are as central as possible during Intemperance One and Intemperance Two to ensure you’re going to hit everyone.</description></item><item><title>Paladin Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 03:22:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Paladin Leveling Dungeon Tips Keeping Aggro Turn on Iron Will and never turn it off. As long as you keep hitting the mobs, you will have aggro on them. In multi-target situations, use AoE so that you can keep aggro on all mobs.
Pulling Mobs There are a variety of ways to ensure you pull all of the mobs in a pack quickly and reliably, without stopping on your way to the next pack of mobs.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</guid><description>by Io Whitespirit (Faerie)
FOREWORD One of the biggest requests I have had is a more concise document on what people “need to know” before jumping into more difficult content. This is not meant to be a replacement for a general guide to Dancer; please see Ringabel’s extensive write-up instead, which will be linked at the end of the document in the appendix.
This guide will be broken down into three sections: Basics, Intermediate, and Advanced.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:13:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/openers/</guid><description>OPENER INFOGRAPHIC Full Size
Pre-Pull: -15s: Standard Step (Step, Step)
Peloton
-1.5s: Current Tincture of Dexterity
Pull: Standard Finish
Technical Step (Step, Step, Step, Step)
Technical Finish (Devilment) Starfall Dance (Flourish, Fan Dance III) Tillana (Fan Dance IV) Saber Dance/Crit Fountainfall (if Feather, Fan Dance I, if proc Fan Dance III) Standard Step (Step, Step)\ Standard Finish
Thanks to Moth for the image!</description></item><item><title>Dancer Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type Casting Recast Description Cascade 1 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 220. Fountain 2 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 100. 280 as part of combo. Windmill 15 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 100 to all nearby enemies. Standard Step 15 Ability Instant 30s Begin dancing, granting yourself Standard Step. Standard Finish 15 Ability Instant 1.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/basic-guide/</guid><description>Foreword Welcome to the basic Dancer guide. Within this document, you’ll find all the information you’ll need to learn to play the job. Other links will be included below for further references and resources. Any further questions can also be directed to the Dancer channels in the Balance’s Discord.
For a video version of this guide click here!
Useful Resources Skill Overview
Opener Infographic
Io&amp;rsquo;s Raiding Primer
Ringabel&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Guide</description></item><item><title>Dancer Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:10:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Leveling Guide for Dancer (DNC) Written by: Ringabel Dim
This information on this page is to give useful tips to help you as you are leveling DNC. This guide will focus on which skills and abilities are available to you in each level range, and will indicate at which levels you get actions that affect your rotation and how they affect it.
Basics Gear First of all, the gear you get from the quest unlocking DNC is not the best gear you can wear on DNC at level 60.</description></item><item><title>Abyssos</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/abyssos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 18:05:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/abyssos/</guid><description>For information on Addle and Magick Barrier usage, see https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ
P5S Potion Usage Due to the fight being ten minutes long, using potion off cooldown for progression is recommended as that will get you three potions before enrage. However, it is fairly common for even undergeared parties to kill the boss before or around nine minutes, with kill times going as fast as near seven minutes now.
With this in mind, it is usually better to use your first potion at two minutes with a triple combo.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>White Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>White Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description>In general this will boil down to choosing max item level gear with sufficient Piety while maximizing Crit, then melding Crit &amp;gt; DH/DET where possible, though Piety melds can be useful in a pinch if you end up too low.
Piety is a binary stat, as any more than you needed to not run out of mp was wasted stats. Because of this, when choosing our substats, avoiding excess Piety is the best way for us to increase our damage, and you&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes see our low piety sets use lower iLvl equipment to avoid Piety (this is still the exception rather than the rule, don&amp;rsquo;t actively use lower iLvl items to dodge Piety without calculating out the gain yourself).</description></item><item><title>White Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:35:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>White Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</guid><description>Standard Opener In most cases, use this:
-3s Pre-pull Current Tincture of Mind
-1.5s Pre-pull Glare III
PULL
Dia
Glare III
Glare III Weave: Presence of Mind
Glare III Weave: Assize Glare III (etc.)
This opener uses both PoM and Assize under raid buffs, Assize is weaved under PoM which can cause clipping even at moderate ping, in most cases this will not be an issue.
(To view the image full size click here.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:33:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Gear and Job Quests Keep up to date with job quests; job quests will give you solid spells or vital gear. Make sure your gear has mind stat on it. You should always aim to keep your gear up to date, roll for dungeon gear with mind, and spend your tomestones on tomestone gear to equip it when you hit 50, 60, 70, and 80. You can find the vendors in Mor Dhona (50), Idyllshire (60), Rhalgr&amp;rsquo;s Reach (70), and Eulmore (80).</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:46:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 (now updated for 6.x). Introduction Dark Knight (DRK) is one of the four tanks available in Final Fantasy XIV: Endwalker. Its rotation features large bursts of damage, accompanied by spikes in actions per minute (APM) and requires managing both MP and a Blood Gauge, putting many hard-hitting attacks into party raid buff windows. It also has access to one of the most powerful single-target mitigation abilities available in The Blackest Night (TBN).</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:46:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</guid><description>Dark Knight Openers and Rotation Dark Knight Openers DRK has several different options for openers, not all of which are listed here. Fight timings and party composition can both affect which opener is best, based on when you can keep uptime on the boss and when raid buffs are used. Fight-specific opener information can be found in #drk_encounter and #drk_questions (often in the pins). This section will list some General-purpose DRK openers which work relatively well in most situations.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:45:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions Why can’t I fit five GCDs in Blood Weapon (or Delirium)? The single most likely reason is that you aren’t weaving Blood Weapon late into the GCD. As long as you are weaving Blood Weapon late and keeping the GCD rolling during it, five GCDs in Blood Weapon should be very consistent. With high latency (100+ ms), double weaves can cause the last GCD to fall out of Blood Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction While this guide is not intended as a complete resource for tanking in dungeons and trials, the following sections will provide a brief primer for those new to the role or who need a refresher. If you are already confident in your job as a tank, feel free to skip ahead to the last section, which covers the evolution of your rotation as you level up to max.
Gearing Your primary focus until you reach level cap is to accumulate as much defense and vitality as possible in order to stay alive.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:44:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</guid><description>Dark Knight Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Single Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Hard Slash HS 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 170. Syphon Strike SS 2 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 260. Restores 600 MP.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Reaper Advanced Rotational Theory Contributors: Dook Prime, Torael Valdis, Rin Karigani, Laille Ormesaing, Shalfu Nyan. Special thanks to Moth Kira and Jackal for the infographs! rDPS vs. aDPS and Reaper I wanted to start this guide off with talking about the FFLogs metrics and how they relate to Reaper, as well as how they can and should be used to measure performance. Currently, as it stands, FFLogs has three main metrics it measures DPS with:</description></item><item><title>Machinist Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 02:35:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single-Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heated Split Shot HS1 54 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 200. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Split Shot. Heated Slug Shot HS2 60 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 300. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Slug Shot. Heated Clean Shot HS3 64 Weaponskill 2.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 02:34:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Simple Pointers for New Machinists Unlocking new jobs can be daunting, so to alleviate some of the stress of all of the new actions, here’s some tips to help the new Machinists understand their rotation while leveling and gain some insight into how everything comes together! Reference the weaponskills and abilities in the beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide if you forget exactly what things do. For clarity purposes:
GCDs are your weaponskills. They are tied to a timer related to your skill speed.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</guid><description>Openers It is important that you attempt to put as much damage into the raid buffs of your party as possible. Wildfire does not scale with skill speed, so once it’s placed in your opener it will never move forward and can only be delayed in your rotation. Wildfire should be placed properly in the opener based on your party composition and the downtime you have in an encounter. Wildfire snapshots raid buffs upon use of the ability &amp;ndash; not on detonation.</description></item><item><title>Machinist FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:33:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions When do I use Hypercharge?
You can use Hypercharge freely when above 50 heat as long as four conditions are met:
Drill and Air Anchor have more than eight to ten seconds left on cooldown You will not break your combo. (It will break if you try to carry it over HC + Drill + Anchor.) You have 0-1 Gauss Round and Ricochet charges stored. You are using Wildfire or will have enough heat for it later when you need it.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Bard Leveling Guide Gear Always use the gear with the highest dexterity available to you. This is more important than any secondary stat - you should not worry about those until endgame.
Aside from some early quest rewards and vendor gear bought for gil, a piece&amp;rsquo;s item level correlates to its Dexterity. So you can just use the highest item level gear and you&amp;rsquo;ll be good to go.
Bards use &amp;ldquo;Aiming&amp;rdquo; gear, so if you see that label on a coffer quest reward, that one is for you.</description></item><item><title>Bard Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</guid><description>Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find notes and clarifications about Bard&amp;rsquo;s skills. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for tooltips, check the official website.
GCDs (share a Global Cooldown) Burst Shot (BS) Your go-to filler GCD on single targets. Use Burst Shot when you have no other GCDs you need to press. Refulgent Arrow (RA) Refulgent Arrow is usable when you have the not so aptly-named &amp;ldquo;Straight Shot Ready&amp;rdquo; buff. You can get this buff by using Burst Shot, Stormbite, Caustic Bite, Iron Jaws, or Barrage.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes Thin Air has two charges but only reduces mana cost on one spell per cast. Glare cast time reduced to 1.5s. Presence of Mind changes to a 120s cooldown. Damage GCD Glare III Single target damage (310), 1.5 cast time At lower levels you&amp;rsquo;ll have Stone, which gets replaced by Glare at level 72 Can weave one oGCD after it Cast this when you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything else.</description></item><item><title>Bard Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</guid><description>Welcome to the Basics Guide for Bard! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a fresh level 90, a returning player, or just need a refresher, this guide will get you started and help you feel comfortable.
This is a basic introduction to level 90 Bard. It will not go into many nuances, optimizations, or topics outside of playing the job in battle.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for such information, you may find it in one of the dedicated guides below:</description></item><item><title>Reaper FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:49:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dragonsong's Reprise (Ultimate)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/fight-tips/dragonsong-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 04:36:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/fight-tips/dragonsong-war/</guid><description>Reaper Guide for Dragonsong’s Reprise (Ultimate) Introduction: Dragonsong’s Reprise (Ultimate) is the first Ultimate released in Final Fantasy XIV: Endwalker. This entire encounter is about 22 minutes long and split into seven Phases and one Intermission: The Vault Knights, King Thordan, Nidhogg, The Eyes, Rewind Intermission, King Thordan II, The Great Wyrms, and The Dragon King. This guide will go over the rotational structure for Reaper in this encounter and provide tips for different push-timings, Arcane Circle and pot examples, Opener and give some general ideas for how to execute your burst.</description></item><item><title>Dragonsong's Reprise (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/dragonsongs-reprise-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:41:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/dragonsongs-reprise-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>Introduction In this raid, only three phases in particular have what most would consider to be tight DPS checks (Nidhogg, Eyes, Dragon King Thordan), and one with a moderate one (Double Dragons). The Double Dragons phase DPS check is low in terms of boss HP relative to enrage timer, but in practice can feel high for people who struggle to keep uptime amid its mechanics.
Other phases, however, are much more lenient with minimal uptime considerations.</description></item><item><title>Samurai Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:15:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/samurai/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:15:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:14:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:13:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Ninja Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 23:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/openers/</guid><description>Opener The most up to date Astrologian opener(s) can always be found in the #ast_resources channel on The Balance Discord. Keep in mind that Astrologian openers are extremely flexible and depend almost entirely on the circumstances of the fight, the timings of the planned raid DPS bursts, and party composition. Any premade Astrologian opener is a generic framework, not a universally optimal opener.
We&amp;rsquo;ve taken a lot of care to evaluate as many of the variables as we reasonably can and identify the core methodology of the most statistically successful opener with regard to when most DPS jobs burst the hardest and when other raid buffs should be coming out, assuming everyone is doing a proper opener.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 23:34:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide is intended to help you level Astrologian to level 90 from any given starting point, while also beginning to slowly suggest fundamental strategies and techniques. Habits develop early, and practice makes permanent.
This guide is not intended to be a complete guide on how to heal in dungeons, trials, or any other content. However, the following section is intended to give some strategies to the mindset of a healer in XIV, and I recommend you read it if you have never been a healer in specifically XIV-related max-level content before.</description></item><item><title>Dragoon Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 20:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/dragoon/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Due to the nature of the Dragoon job design, advanced content is included and covered within the Basic Guide. If you have further questions regarding DRG optimization, please feel free to ask in the Discord server.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:12:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gunbreaker Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 21:07:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Leveling Guide Like any other class, you may have to do lower level content and of course will need to Level from level 60 to level 90 if forgoing a jump book. So, it’s important to keep on top of GNB, especially at Level 70 due to sync for The Weapon’s Refrain (Ultimate) and The Unending Coil of Bahamut (Ultimate).
No Mercy is unlocked at level 2, so it’s used in all forms of content from the beginning of A Realm Reborn up to current content in Endwalker.</description></item><item><title>Gunbreaker FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 21:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/gunbreaker/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dancer Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 13:03:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dancer FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</guid><description>DANCE PARTNER PRIORITY This list is made in a gear/skill vacuum. This is the recommended partner priority list.
Special Note: some fights may favor certain Dance Partners over others based on phases/mechanics or ability to hit multiple targets.
Updated: January 19, 2021 to account for balance changes in patch 5.4.
SAM NIN MNK / BLM (crit build)* DRG / SMN RDM MCH BRD DNC *Data on BLM SpS build as a dance partner is not available due to length in time to reach BiS with this build as of this update, but value as a dance partner is believed to drop significantly between the two builds due to under utilization of Devilment.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 06:40:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/ninja/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Monk Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 08:04:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Job Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 08:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 07:55:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 07:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Due to the nature of the SMN job changes, advanced content is included in the Basic Guide. If you have further questions, feel free to ask in the Discord.
Contact us if you would like to contribute to this guide.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/openers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 07:52:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/openers/</guid><description>Openers Titan First Opener The below opener is the general go to opener for summoner and uses Titan as the first primal. Since the 6.1 changes, we can now use Searing Light in Bahamut, and choose to do so after the Bahamut GCD to avoid using a &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; GCD in our buff. You can choose to omit the precast Ruin III and use Bahamut at 0s as well. This may be an optimization strategy for particular fight timelines or encounters where the gained one second on cycle progression may matter.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 06:39:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This is the Basic Guide for Astrologian. This will cover enough ground to get you started with AST, being able to handle this relatively high-input job in content at level 90. It is intended to be well-suited for any player, and if you take the advice and techniques from this guide you should be able to handle yourself well-enough in endgame content.
As this guide is relatively basic and does not go into any of the complexities of Astrologian, there will, of course, be gaps of knowledge, and some aspects of this fairly high-intensity job will be glossed over.</description></item><item><title>Sage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/openers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 06:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/openers/</guid><description>Standard Opener Full Size
Pneuma Opener Full Size</description></item><item><title>Sage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 06:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 05:32:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction While Sage starts out at level 70, you may find yourself synced to lower level ranges when leveling through roulettes, and this guide aims to cover what options you have at each level range. Even if you want to level Sage exclusively using 70+ content, you can use this guide as an explanation of your large mitigation/healing toolkit and how they work together with a focus on healing dungeon content; though the guidelines introduced are applicable to all PvE content in this game.</description></item><item><title>Sage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 05:29:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Sage: The Basics Welcome to the basic guide for Sage, which should give you everything you need to get started. This guide is meant to be fairly basic and does not cover every little detail. However, it should point you in the right general direction and give you a feel for the class.
Author and Acknowledgements This guide was written by Wynn Dohz, with special thanks to Shy and all the other healer mentors.</description></item><item><title>Sage Job Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 05:58:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 05:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 22:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Hello! In this guide, you will find a series of details and optimizations for Endwalker Bard.
This builds on the Bard Basic Guide and expects you to be familiar with Bard&amp;rsquo;s skills, general priorities, opener, and song cycle.
Topics are ordered based on some mix of importance and flow. It is a little all over the place, but such is the nature of a kit like Bard&amp;rsquo;s.
The two-minute burst Like many jobs, Bard&amp;rsquo;s kit revolves around a big damage burst every two minutes, alongside a powerful duo of party-wide buffs, Battle Voice and Radiant Finale.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 04:58:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes New Skills: Astrodyne, Macrocosmos, Exaltation, Minor Arcana. Sleeve Draw and Nocturnal Sect has been removed. Draw has gained two charges. Damage GCDs Fall Malefic
Single target damage (250), 1.5 cast time. Cast this when you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything else. Can weave one oGCD after this. Gravity II
AoE damage in a 5y radius around your target (130 potency), 1.5s cast time. In dungeons, apply Combust while running and spam gravity when the tank stops.</description></item><item><title>The Unending Coil of Bahamut (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 01:09:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>General Fight Tips Manafication Manafication’s damage buff and 110 second cooldown is granted by a trait at Lv.74 meaning that in Lv.70 content it functions the same way it did in Stormblood: with no damage buff and a 120s cooldown. As a result of there being no damage buff it should be used slightly differently than in level 80 and 90 content.
While you should still aim to finish phases with as much Black and White mana as possible, in the scenario that your mana is at 50 | 50 or below, you can use Manafication during downtime during or between phases to get it on cooldown faster.</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos Raid Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 03:47:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>6.x BLM Raid Guide By: Rika Vanih
Overview This document will go over various recommendations and information relevant to playing Black Mage for various endgame fights for Endwalker. Keep in mind that these are just generalized tips to be used as a starting point–there may be different strats, killtimes, or other personal optimizations which may require alternative planning that will deviate from the suggestions in this document. If you have any questions/comments or feel like something is missing that would be valuable to add, feel free to give your input over in the Black Mage channels in the Balance.</description></item><item><title>Monk Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:05:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Know Your Role Melee DPS jobs have a unique mechanic in positionals. Certain actions will deal more damage when executed from the rear or flank of a target. Targets with continuous Target Rings will always take the increased damage from positional actions. The Role Action True North allows you to disregard positional requirements for ten seconds per use.
While it is a loss to miss your Positionals, landing them should be your last priority, after you have met all of the other combat priority requirements of a melee DPS job.</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos Raid Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 19:24:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>Red Mage Asphodelos Encounter Advice For information on Addle and Magick Barrier usage, see https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ
P1S Intemperance Embolden should be used on cooldown, with the two-minute and six-minute buff windows occurring during Intemperance.
For the first Intemperance, as there is a delay between the Intemperance cast and the first set of tiles exploding, you can stand in the center of the arena to cast Embolden before moving out to your tile.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 03:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome! This page is written to assist you throughout your leveling journey and provide insight on how the Summoner job will evolve from level one to level 80. Summoner may appear as a bit of a “unique” job with a lot of moving parts and multiple avenues of attacking enemies. Throughout this leveling guide, we will provide you with a basic fundamental understanding of each spell that you will unlock, as well as provide some quick rotation priorities and visualization examples.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 06:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Machinist Guide Welcome to the Basic Machinist Guide! Within this document, you&amp;rsquo;ll find all the information you&amp;rsquo;ll need to play the job well. The links below can be used as teleports to other pages if you need the information while learning the job. Any questions can be directed to the Machinist channels in our Discord.
Openers
Advanced Guide
Video Guide
Gearing and Meld Priority
Skills Overview
Frequently Asked Questions</description></item><item><title>Summoner Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type Casting Recast Description Summon Carbuncle 2 Spell 1.5s 2.5s Summons Carbuncle to your side. Radient Aegis 2 Ability Instant 60s Orders Carbuncle to execute Radiant Aegis.Radiant Aegis Effect: Creates a barrier around self that absorbs damage totaling 20% of your maximum HPDuration: 30sMaximum Charges: 2Can only be executed while Carbuncle is summoned. Physick 4 Spell 1.5s 2.5s Restores target&amp;rsquo;s HP.Cure Potency: 400 Gemshine 6 Spell 2.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:18:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:18:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dark Knight Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:17:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 06:04:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Advanced SGE Guide Sage being relatively straightforward means that there&amp;rsquo;s not all that much for an &amp;ldquo;advanced&amp;rdquo; guide to cover. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cover some of the areas that aren&amp;rsquo;t covered in the basic guide.
Phlegma Timings With the rework of Trick Attack in 6.1, it is no longer necessary to worry about odd-minute buff windows, as they no longer exist. Rather, any Phlegma that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used in a two-minute buff window becomes free movement.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 09:16:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/stat-priority/</guid><description>As a general rule we recommend:
SpS to 2.46-2.48 &amp;gt; Crit &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt;= DH &amp;gt; More SpS
There is an alternative way to play the job that focuses on maximizing SpS and minimizing Crit instead, which would use this priority:
SpS &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt;= DH &amp;gt; Crit
In general, the Crit set appears better for most situations. Spell speed as a stat excels when it can be fine-tuned around a fight’s timeline, but you can choose to use the SpS set blindly if you wish.</description></item><item><title>Monk Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Astrologian FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 05:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/faq/</guid><description>What Sect Should I Use? Diurnal remains generally very efficient, but buffs to Celestial Opposition and Celestial Intersection reduce the reliance on GCD healing (which is where Nocturnal Sect primarily falls short of Diurnal), and Nocturnal Intersection is very strong. The gap in overall efficiency between Diurnal and Nocturnal Sect is still quite significant, but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t put you off of using Nocturnal Sect when the situation calls for it.</description></item><item><title>White Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 04:43:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</guid><description>White Mage FAQ How should movement and weaving be handled? White Mage (WHM) is one of the least mobile jobs in the game, and so planning movement is critical to success. Below is a list of available options; keep in mind that it’s heavily subjective based on the encounter and your party.
Pre-position with slidecasts and natural Dia refreshes Natural Dia refresh (&amp;lt; ~3s remaining), slidecast, or Swiftcast + Glare (not clipped, always consider holding for raise in prog) Rapture that does useful healing, Misery Regen that does necessary healing (rare in Savage and below) Overheal Lilies Dia outside natural refresh (almost always avoidable) Extended movements involve a combination of these roughly in order of priority, and a lot of movement can be minimized with proper prepositioning utilizing a combination of Dia and slidecasting.</description></item><item><title>Bard FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 04:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</guid><description>Single target FAQ When should I use Raging Strikes after the opener?
A couple of GCDs into Minuet. This is to cover as much Pitch Perfect potential as possible.
When do I use my second/third potion?
Try to cover Raging Strikes and Barrage with it. That damage spike is bigger than any heap of party buffs. If you can, also try to pop it right before an Iron Jaws, so that you can IJ at the end and get two runs of buffed DoTs.</description></item><item><title>Monk FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:17:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</guid><description>Is Double True Strike dead?
As purely the best option, yup, go back to 1:1 Twin Snakes and True.
What&amp;rsquo;s with the double Dragon Kick in the openers?
With Standard, you DK after Perfect Balance for DK&amp;rsquo;s higher potency and again later to gain Leaden finally. With Early Buff a stanceless Leaden Boot after PB is worse on average than using the DK to guarantee a crit one.
What do non opener RoF windows look like?</description></item><item><title>Dancer Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:18:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 07:10:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/sage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Machinist Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 06:19:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 22:51:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</guid><description>Bard Openers For all openers:
Use Pitch Perfect at three stacks as able, Bloodletter as able, and Refulgent procs as you get them. Hold Barrage until the next GCD if you already have an Refulgent proc. The best potion as of 6.00 is high-quality Grade 5 Tincture of Dexterity. Opener FAQ Is it really okay to use Radiant Finale for only 2% in the opener?
Yes, by the next two-minute burst you will have gotten three more coda.</description></item><item><title>Astrologian Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/astrologian/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Becoming A Better Tank</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</guid><description>Version 1.0 Torael Valdis | Jenova (NA) | Torael_Valdis#8120
This guide is written with the intention to be hosted on The Balance Discord and should not be hosted elsewhere without consent of the owner.
Table of Contents Introduction
Mindset
Mitigation
Mitigating As The Off Tank Facilitating Party Uptime
Damage
Consistency and Adaptability
Closing Thoughts
Special Thanks Changelog Intro “What is Tanking: Tanking in Final Fantasy 14, in the most basic of ideas, is controlling the Enmity of the enemies and reducing the damage you take from said enemies.</description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/pages/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/pages/credits/</guid><description>Contributors Devs Nono Skye Hint Scrubby OHaiDanny Roxas SneakyCrow ductapeofdoom Hughes89 Lunarrize ArcaneDisgea axheron Content Editing / Layout Laille Elleiana Ana Doubt Karasu Wilco Lyall Frontend Moth Screenshot Credits Rose Ophelia Javed Moolye Pato Bolo Kotomi Dragomir Kaleigh Leslie-Taylor Mika Games Galaio Catelyn Mallister Ailarra Thurisaz Hutch Ana Val Rainteaux HoennAngel N. W. Raymond Holley Limitless Blue</description></item><item><title>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide/</guid><description>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide
Introduction This is a comprehensive guide aimed towards players entering endgame — Level 90 — for the first time and getting overwhelmed with Final Fantasy XIV&amp;rsquo;s gear progression systems. This guide will help you get an understanding of how FFXIV’s endgame systems work, as well as how to gear up and what types of endgame PvE content exist.
Step 1. Get AF gear, finish MSQ, and farm Tomestones for gear.</description></item><item><title>Guide to Leveling Reaper and Sage Immediately in Endwalker</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/guide-to-leveling-reaper-and-sage-immediately-in-endwalker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/guide-to-leveling-reaper-and-sage-immediately-in-endwalker/</guid><description>Written by: Ringabel Dim (DNC Mentor in The Balance)
On November 19th - Early Access of Endwalker, many players may be interested in leveling either Reaper or Sage as their first job in the new expansion. This guide provides info on what to prepare and how to optimize your time to level from 70 to 80 as quick as possible.
EXP Sources to Prepare Before Endwalker is Released: Wondrous Tails (roughly 50%): Pick up Wondrous Tails in Idyllshire on the week of Tuesday, November 9th.</description></item><item><title>Tanking FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-faq/</guid><description>Tanking FAQ What Food / Potion do tanks use? Grade 4 Tincture of Strength Chicken Fettuccine OR Smoked Chicken What do I meld? Read the &amp;ldquo;Stats&amp;rdquo; section
Why is my combo breaking? The combo timer is exactly 15 seconds long. This means that you can do the following:
Combo 1 Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Combo 2 As long as the time between the cast of Combo 1 and Combo 2 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exceed 15s.</description></item><item><title>Tanking Stats and Materia</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Tanking Stats and Materia Stats Stat Priority Weapon Damage Main stat (Str/Vit on tanks) Substats There are no &amp;ldquo;Stat weights&amp;rdquo;.
Weapon Damage almost always comes with main stat increase.
Higher item level almost always comes with main stat increase.
Upgrade your gear as often as possible
Skill Speed (at level 80) 2.43s GCD - 1015 SkS 2.42s GCD - 1117 SkS 2.41s GCD - 1218 SkS 2.40s GCD - 1320 SkS 2.</description></item><item><title>Zyrk's Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</guid><description>Zyrk’s FFXIV Shadowbringers Healing Guide Learn how to hate your party, the game, and yourself About the Author Hi, I’m Zyrkhan Dar’locke. My name is blue on The Balance, and that’s basically all I have to say for myself. You may also know me as “what?” and “literally who.” I’m here to talk about healing and stuff, because I guess I like it or something, mostly because I don’t respect myself.</description></item></channel></rss>