<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dancer on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/</link><description>Recent content in Dancer on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 12:05:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dancer Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 12:05:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Best-in-Slot (BiS) / Itemization Best-in-slot New BiS (5.55) with iLvl 535 Relic Weapon Old BiS (5.4) with Edenmorn Weapon - (watch melds)
BiS Food: Smoked Chicken
BiS Potion: Grade 4 Tincture of Dexterity
Meld Priority Crit &amp;gt; DH &amp;gt; DET
Gearing Up Guide Guide to gearing DNC (5.58) - includes starting gear and tomestone buy order
Best starting gearset before accessing any weekly savage gear pieces or spending Tomestones of Revelation: view this Starting Gearset on Etro.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</guid><description>by Io Whitespirit (Faerie)
FOREWORD One of the biggest requests I have had is a more concise document on what people “need to know” before jumping into more difficult content. This is not meant to be a replacement for a general guide to Dancer; please see Ringabel’s extensive write-up instead, which will be linked at the end of the document in the appendix.
This guide will be broken down into three sections: Basics, Intermediate, and Advanced.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:13:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/openers/</guid><description>OPENER INFOGRAPHIC Full Size
Pre-Pull: -15s: Standard Step (Step, Step)
Peloton
-1.5s: Current Tincture of Dexterity
Pull: Standard Finish
Technical Step (Step, Step, Step, Step)
Technical Finish (Devilment) Starfall Dance (Flourish, Fan Dance III) Tillana (Fan Dance IV) Saber Dance/Crit Fountainfall (if Feather, Fan Dance I, if proc Fan Dance III) Standard Step (Step, Step)\ Standard Finish
Thanks to Moth for the image!</description></item><item><title>Dancer Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type Casting Recast Description Cascade 1 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 220. Fountain 2 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 100. 280 as part of combo. Windmill 15 Weaponskill Instant 2.5s Delivers an attack with a potency of 100 to all nearby enemies. Standard Step 15 Ability Instant 30s Begin dancing, granting yourself Standard Step. Standard Finish 15 Ability Instant 1.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/basic-guide/</guid><description>Foreword Welcome to the basic Dancer guide. Within this document, you’ll find all the information you’ll need to learn to play the job. Other links will be included below for further references and resources. Any further questions can also be directed to the Dancer channels in the Balance’s Discord.
For a video version of this guide click here!
Useful Resources Skill Overview
Opener Infographic
Io&amp;rsquo;s Raiding Primer
Ringabel&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Guide</description></item><item><title>Dancer Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:10:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Leveling Guide for Dancer (DNC) Written by: Ringabel Dim
This information on this page is to give useful tips to help you as you are leveling DNC. This guide will focus on which skills and abilities are available to you in each level range, and will indicate at which levels you get actions that affect your rotation and how they affect it.
Basics Gear First of all, the gear you get from the quest unlocking DNC is not the best gear you can wear on DNC at level 60.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 13:03:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dancer FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</guid><description>DANCE PARTNER PRIORITY This list is made in a gear/skill vacuum. This is the recommended partner priority list.
Special Note: some fights may favor certain Dance Partners over others based on phases/mechanics or ability to hit multiple targets.
Updated: January 19, 2021 to account for balance changes in patch 5.4.
SAM NIN MNK / BLM (crit build)* DRG / SMN RDM MCH BRD DNC *Data on BLM SpS build as a dance partner is not available due to length in time to reach BiS with this build as of this update, but value as a dance partner is believed to drop significantly between the two builds due to under utilization of Devilment.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:18:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>