<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dark Knight on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/</link><description>Recent content in Dark Knight on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 08:36:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dark Knight Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 08:36:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/openers/</guid><description>Dark Knight Openers and Rotation Dark Knight Openers DRK is a flexible class, and so specific encounters may benefit from alternate openers. Encounter-specific opener information may be found in the drk_encounter channel of the Balance discord, or on fight-specific guides, where applicable. This section will list general-purpose DRK openers, which work well for most situations, and provide an overview of how openers are chosen.
Opener Design Goals Use as many big hits and spend as much MP as possible inside potion and raid buff windows (which typically come up around the third or fourth GCD).</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:16:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/best-in-slot/</guid><description>Dark Knight Best In Slot Day one prog set(s) will be listed immediately when a new tier is released, but pre-BiS sets will otherwise not be maintained on this page. Use the Tank Gear Manager (https://bit.ly/TankDPSCalc520) to make your own gearing decisions based on what gear is available to you. Prioritizing item level over substats is generally recommended while learning new encounters.
Note: Early progression gear will often provide very different skill speed values from BiS.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:46:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction to Dark Knight The useless pre-Endwalker guide by nikroulah#1605 (now updated for 6.x and 7.x). Introduction Dark Knight (DRK) is one of the four tanks available in Final Fantasy XIV: Endwalker. Its rotation features large bursts of damage, accompanied by spikes in actions per minute (APM) and requires managing both MP and a Blood Gauge, putting many hard-hitting attacks into party raid buff windows. It also has access to one of the most powerful single-target mitigation abilities available in The Blackest Night (TBN).</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:45:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions Why can’t I fit five GCDs in Blood Weapon (or Delirium)? The single most likely reason is that you aren’t weaving Blood Weapon late into the GCD. As long as you are weaving Blood Weapon late and keeping the GCD rolling during it, five GCDs in Blood Weapon should be very consistent. With high latency (100+ ms), double weaves can cause the last GCD to fall out of Blood Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction While this guide is not intended as a complete resource for tanking in dungeons and trials, the following sections will provide a brief primer for those new to the role or who need a refresher. If you are already confident in your job as a tank, feel free to skip ahead to the last section, which covers the evolution of your rotation as you level up to max.
Gearing Your primary focus until you reach level cap is to accumulate as much defense and vitality as possible in order to stay alive.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:44:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/skills-overview/</guid><description>Dark Knight Skills Overview Abilities will be presented in a tabular format for easy reading.
Actions used in Single Target Rotation Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Hard Slash HS 1 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 300. Syphon Strike SS 2 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second action in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 380.</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:13:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Dark Knight Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:12:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dark Knight Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:17:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/dark-knight/job-changes/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>