<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scholar on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/</link><description>Recent content in Scholar on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:54:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scholar Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:54:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended for the casual player looking for advice on how to play Scholar in leveling dungeons. Below, we’ll briefly describe all Scholar actions, grouped by level, and some general guidelines for when to use them. For more detailed ability descriptions, please consult the in-game tooltips or job guide, and if you’d like to learn more about playing and optimizing Scholar, check out our other guides.
Quick Glossary SCH: Scholar CD (Cooldown): The time it takes before you’re able to cast an action again.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/basic-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended for players who are looking to play Scholar in level 90 trials and raids. For information about playing Scholar while leveling, please see our Leveling Guide.
Quick Glossary SCH: Scholar CD (Cooldown): The time it takes before you’re able to cast an action again. GCD (Global Cooldown): Spells that share the same base recast time. On SCH, these are mostly spells with about 2.5s recast time, plus Resurrection.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:53:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes Broil IV cast time is reduced to 1.5s base cast time. You can weave one oGCD after it without clipping. Do not use Ruin II for weaving. New skills: Protraction and Expedient Shields apply at the slidecast window. It is now possible to cast Adloquium and immediately use Deployment Tactics, but this is still not recommended because this will clip GCD. Energy Drain no longer restores MP. Aetherflow MP is increased but this is a net loss for players who averaged 3+ Energy Drains per minute (including Energy Drains from Dissipation).</description></item><item><title>Scholar Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/openers/</guid><description>Remember that the exact ability usage in these openers is not strict. If you need to use a heal in the opener or hold an AF stack for later healing do so. This is the ability usage you&amp;rsquo;d do on a dummy, but not every fight allows for it.
Chain Stratagem is varied, there are several factors that impact its usage within a raid setting. Usually, it is dependent on composition, but may also need to be adjusted for fight timings, though these situations are fairly rare.</description></item><item><title>Scholar FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/faq/</guid><description>Scholar FAQ How can I see my fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate in battle?
A. Character Configuration &amp;gt; Control Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Target&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Target Settings&amp;rdquo;, Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Disable targeting of pets and minions when in battle.&amp;rdquo;
B. Character Config &amp;gt; Display Name Settings &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Own&amp;rdquo; tab &amp;gt; Under &amp;ldquo;Pets&amp;rdquo; set &amp;ldquo;Display Name Settings&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Always&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;During Battle&amp;rdquo;
Both options must be set this way or your fairy&amp;rsquo;s nameplate will be hidden.</description></item><item><title>Scholar Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scholar Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 02:52:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/stat-priority/</guid><description>Consider melding Det over DH for prog, as the damage benefits are basically equal on average. Meld SpS to a comfy tier if you wish, low priority during prog.
Piety is a binary stat, as any more than you needed to not run out of mp was wasted stats. Because of this, when choosing our substats, avoiding excess Piety is the best way for us to increase our damage, and you&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes see our low piety sets use lower iLvl equipment to avoid Piety (this is still the exception rather than the rule, don&amp;rsquo;t actively use lower iLvl items to dodge Piety without calculating out the gain yourself).</description></item><item><title>Scholar Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>Scholar Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:18:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/job-changes/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>