<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCH on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/mch/</link><description>Recent content in MCH on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/mch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machinist Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Machinist Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended to give the reader the tools needed to approach encounter optimization as a Machinist. It assumes you are already familiar with the fundamentals of the job – if you need a refresher, please read the Basic Guide and come back when you&amp;rsquo;re done.
Introduction to Optimization This section will introduce some core concepts for optimizing encounters in FFXIV. If you are already familiar with optimization on other jobs, you can feel free to skip ahead!</description></item><item><title>Machinist Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 02:35:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single-Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heated Split Shot HS1 54 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 200. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Split Shot. Heated Slug Shot HS2 60 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 300. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Slug Shot. Heated Clean Shot HS3 64 Weaponskill 2.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</guid><description>Openers It is important that you attempt to put as much damage into the raid buffs of your party as possible. Wildfire does not scale with skill speed, so once it’s placed in your opener it will never move forward and can only be delayed in your rotation. Wildfire should be placed properly in the opener based on your party composition and the downtime you have in an encounter. Wildfire snapshots raid buffs upon use of the ability &amp;ndash; not on detonation.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 06:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Machinist Guide Welcome to the Basic Machinist Guide! Within this document, you&amp;rsquo;ll find all the information you&amp;rsquo;ll need to play the job well. The links below can be used as teleports to other pages if you need the information while learning the job. Any questions can be directed to the Machinist channels in our Discord.
Openers
Advanced Guide
Video Guide
Gearing and Meld Priority
Skills Overview
Frequently Asked Questions</description></item></channel></rss>