<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Futures Rewritten (Ultimate) RDM Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/futures-rewritten-ultimate-rdm-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/futures-rewritten-ultimate-rdm-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raid has some of the more lenient DPS checks in terms of on-content Ultimate fights. However, as the first two phases are quite downtime-heavy, the difficulty of the DPS checks in those phases will vary greatly depending on your composition, so you may find yourself having to shift your damage around these first two phases a fair bit. Additionally, this fight sees a much larger population of double caster compositions than prior Ultimate fights, due to the popularity of Pictomancer in the fight. This guide will account for as many scenarios as possible regarding damage compositions and fake melee positions, although the differences between fake melee and ranged have become much less pronounced due to the 7.4 Manafication changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Weapon's Refrain (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-weapons-refrain-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:25:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-weapons-refrain-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="general-fight-tips"&gt;General Fight Tips&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="managing-resources"&gt;Managing Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to damage scaling in Endwalker, push timings in The Weapon’s Refrain can vary greatly, between groups and even between pulls in the same group. Therefore, you should use this guide for a general idea of how to manage each phase, but keep in mind this may not always work for you, and you should aim to find a timeline that works for you during progression.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Unending Coil of Bahamut (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="general-fight-tips"&gt;General Fight Tips&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="manafication"&gt;Manafication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manafication’s damage buff and 110 second cooldown is granted by a trait at Lv.74 meaning that in Lv.70 content it functions the same way it did in Stormblood: with no damage buff and a 120s cooldown. As a result of there being no damage buff it should be used slightly differently than in level 80 and 90 content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you should still aim to finish phases with as much Black and White mana as possible, in the scenario that your mana is at 50 | 50 or below, you can use Manafication during downtime during or between phases to get it on cooldown faster. This should be done whenever possible to avoid the possibility of losing a use of Manafication throughout the fight, as even with the Dawntrail change, there are no situations where pressing Manafication on cooldown will result in the free combo falling off before the next phase begins.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Omega Protocol (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:22:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-omega-protocol-ultimate/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-omega-protocol-ultimate-rdm-guide"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Omega Protocol (Ultimate) RDM Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raid features a unique mix of multiple tight DPS checks, movement-intensive mechanics requiring real-time adjustment, and flexible optimization potential. That said, with some planning and smart resource management, Red Mage is able to perform well in this raid and bring a lot of value to a party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are six phases in this raid. Generally, every phase has a DPS check that requires some basic optimization, but the difficulty of Phase 2 and Phase 3 DPS checks tend to depend on party composition and buff timings, with Phase 2 benefitting cleave-heavy compositions and Phase 3 benefitting full uptime 2-minute burst compositions. The phases are commonly referred to by their number and will be referenced again as such later in the document. Refer to the below:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dragonsong's Reprise (Ultimate) Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/dragonsongs-reprise-ultimate-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:58:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/dragonsongs-reprise-ultimate-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this raid, only three phases in particular have what most would consider to be tight DPS checks (Nidhogg, Eyes, Dragon King Thordan), and one with a moderate one (Double Dragons). The Double Dragons phase DPS check is low in terms of boss HP relative to enrage timer, but in practice can feel high for people who struggle to keep uptime amid its mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other phases, however, are much more lenient with minimal uptime considerations. So, with RDM being a gauge builder/spender job, we spend much of our time building mana on lenient phases to do more burst damage in the ones with DPS checks that matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Epic of Alexander (Ultimate) RDM Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-epic-of-alexander-ultimate-rdm-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/the-epic-of-alexander-ultimate-rdm-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to damage scaling in Endwalker/Dawntrail and the potential for using fully synced gear, DPS checks in The Epic of Alexander are, on the whole, not extremely tight. Your primary concern for DPS will be the Trio Enrage at the end of Alexander Prime, but with fully synced gear options, phase DPS checks are fairly lenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At level 80, you can fit two full melee combos under Embolden, and this should be your goal whenever possible. There can be some variance in phase kill timings, but if your Manafication is aligned with your buffs, you should always be able to get double a melee combo under each Embolden after the opener.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abyssos</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/abyssos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 18:05:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/abyssos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For information on Addle and Magick Barrier usage, see &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ"&gt;https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="p5s"&gt;P5S&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="potion-usage"&gt;Potion Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the fight being ten minutes long, using potion off cooldown for progression is recommended as that will get you three potions before enrage. However, it is fairly common for even undergeared parties to kill the boss before or around nine minutes, with kill times going as fast as near seven minutes now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, it is usually better to use your first potion at two minutes with a triple combo. The downtime from Devour will naturally lead to most parties using the 4-minute buff window at 4:30 instead, which in turn makes the next buff window come up around 6:30 after Ruby 5, allowing you to use your second potion approximately off cooldown.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Asphodelos Raid Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 19:24:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/fight-tips/asphodelos/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="red-mage-asphodelos-encounter-advice"&gt;Red Mage Asphodelos Encounter Advice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information on Addle and Magick Barrier usage, see &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ"&gt;https://bit.ly/3AHEMxZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="p1s"&gt;P1S&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="intemperance"&gt;Intemperance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embolden should be used on cooldown, with the two-minute and six-minute buff windows occurring during Intemperance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first Intemperance, as there is a delay between the Intemperance cast and the first set of tiles exploding, you can stand in the center of the arena to cast Embolden before moving out to your tile. If you are the designated swap person, you can take advantage of your melee combo to easily accomplish this without losing any uptime.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>