<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Viper on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/</link><description>Recent content in Viper on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:50:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Viper Job Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:50:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Viper Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/stat-priority/</guid><description>Viper follows the stat priority of: Critical Hit &amp;gt; Determination = Direct Hit &amp;gt; Skill Speed. However, it is recommended to use the highest item level gear available to you, as it will give you more of your primary stat which will always result in a higher DPS gain than lower item level counterparts.
When melding with materia, it is advised to follow the same stat priority.</description></item><item><title>Viper Best in Slot</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:49:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Viper Intermediate Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/intermediate-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:48:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/intermediate-guide/</guid><description>Introduction Special thanks to Akashi, Jackal, Azazel, Azrael, Stella, and Rhy whose work religiously theorycrafting this job made this guide possible.
This guide assumes that the player has a firm grasp of the concepts presented in the VPR Basic Guide. If this doesn’t apply to you, give that guide a read before returning here. This guide will be focused on more Intermediate level concepts of VPR, such as burst window optimization with party buffs, planning for downtime, and other rotation optimization.</description></item><item><title>Viper Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/faq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:48:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Viper Standard Opener</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/openers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:47:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/openers/</guid><description> Click here for a larger image.
This is our standard opener for Viper. For more information on what to do after the opener, please see the Basic Guide and Intermediate Guide.</description></item><item><title>Viper Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:47:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/skills-overview/</guid><description>Please note that all of the following actions are based on Viper at level 100, and may not reflect their lower level version effects or potencies.
1. Dual Wield Actions 1.1 Single Target Icon Name Type Recast/Haste Recast Description Steel Fangs Weaponskill 2.50s/2.12s A 200 potency attack that starts the dual wield combo. Potency increased to 300 under the effect of Honed Steel. Grants Honed Reavers for 60 seconds. Reaving Fangs Weaponskill 2.</description></item><item><title>Viper Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:46:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/basic-guide/</guid><description>1﻿. Introduction F﻿irst off, this guide was made possible by the myriad contributions of Akashi, Azazel, Azrael, Jackal, Rhy, and Stella.
P﻿lease note that this guide is intended for Viper at Level 100. For information prior to reaching Level 100, please visit the Leveling Guide.
1﻿.1 Overview Viper (VPR) is a fast-paced melee DPS that alternates between fast dual wield attacks and heavy hitting twinblade attacks. Its core gameplay revolves around the classic builder-spender playstyle, building gauge with its dual wield and twinblade attacks and spending that gauge on a powerful burst window called Reawaken.</description></item><item><title>Viper Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Viper Leveling Guide This guide was written to inform players who are seeking to, or are currently leveling Viper. The guide aims to inform players about how to initially play as Viper, what gear they should use while levelling and where to find it, the key basics of the job, as well as some example openers for lower levels. If you are already a level 100 Viper and are looking for information pertaining to the job at level 100, please see the Viper Basic Guide.</description></item></channel></rss>