<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Viper on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/</link><description>Recent content in Viper on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:16:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:16:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/skills-overview/</guid><description>1. Dual Wield Actions 1.1 Single Target Icon Name Type Recast/Haste Recast Description Steel Fangs Weaponskill 2.50s/2.12s A 200 potency attack that starts the dual wield combo. Dread Fangs Weaponskill 2.50s/2.12s Alternative dual wield combo starter. 100 potency but applies Noxious Gnash for 20 seconds. Noxious Gnash stacks up to 40 seconds and increases the damage the player deals the target by 10%. Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Sting Weaponskill 2.50s/2.12s Combo action that can be used after Steel Fangs or Dread Fangs.</description></item><item><title>Viper Intermediate Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/intermediate-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 05:44:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/intermediate-guide/</guid><description>1. Introduction Special thanks to Akashi, Jackal, Azazel, Azrael, Stella, and Rhy whose work religiously theorycrafting this job made this guide possible.
This guide assumes that the player has a firm grasp of the concepts presented in the VPR Basic Guide. If this doesn’t apply to you, give that guide a read before returning here. This guide will be focused on more Intermediate level concepts of VPR, such as burst window optimization with party buffs, planning for downtime, and other rotation optimization.</description></item><item><title>Viper Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 02:03:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Viper Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 23:50:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/basic-guide/</guid><description>1﻿. Introduction F﻿irst off, this guide was made possible by the myriad contributions of Akashi, Azazel, Azrael, Jackal, Rhy, and Stella.
P﻿lease note that this guide is intended for Viper at Level 100. For information prior to reaching Level 100, please visit the Leveling Guide.
Please note that images in this guide are placeholders for the time being and will be updated with better quality images and graphics when we have access to the HQ icons via the Fan Kit.</description></item><item><title>Viper Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 23:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/viper/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Tentative Viper Leveling Guide THIS WAS WRITTEN PRIOR TO THE FULL RELEASE OF DAWNTRAIL. READ AT YOUR OWN RISK.
This guide was written to inform players who are seeking to, or are currently levelling Viper. The guide aims to inform players about how to initially play as Viper, what gear they should use while levelling and where to find it, the key basics of the job, as well as some example openers for lower levels.</description></item></channel></rss>