<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Summoner on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/</link><description>Recent content in Summoner on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:08:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summoner Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type Casting Recast Description Summon Carbuncle 2 Spell 1.5s 2.5s Summons Carbuncle to your side. Radient Aegis 2 Ability Instant 60s Orders Carbuncle to execute Radiant Aegis.
Radiant Aegis Effect: Creates a barrier around self that absorbs damage totaling 20% of your maximum HP
Duration: 30s
Maximum Charges: 2
Can only be executed while Carbuncle is summoned. Physick 4 Spell 1.5s 2.5s Restores target&amp;rsquo;s HP.
Cure Potency: 400 Gemshine 6 Spell 2.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 03:51:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 03:49:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Due to the nature of the SMN job changes, advanced content is included in the Basic Guide. If you have further questions, feel free to ask in the Discord.
Contact us if you would like to contribute to this guide.</description></item><item><title>Summoner FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 03:48:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 23:35:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide will cover Summoner changes, rotations and ability usage in the Dawntrail expansion. The core foundation of Summoner has not changed significantly from the Endwalker expansion where it received a complete rework. The basic flow and idea of Summoner&amp;rsquo;s rotation can be simplified as follows:
Use Searing Light in alignment with party raid buffs Summon Solar Bahamut and use all abilities to refresh your primal gems Go through three primal phases Summon Bahamut or Phoenix and use all abilities to refresh your primal gems Go through three primal phases Repeat Within that framework, there is additional nuance such as optimizing damage into raid buffs, moving certain spells around based on movement requirements, and making effective use of Summoner&amp;rsquo;s various utility tools.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Job Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 19:49:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summoner Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/stat-priority/</guid><description>As a general rule we recommend:
SpS to 2.46-2.48 &amp;gt; Crit &amp;gt; Det &amp;gt;= DH &amp;gt; More SpS
Previously, SpS was more viable due to the the general potencies being a negligible gain or loss whether the demi phase drifted outside of buffs, but with the addition of Solar Bahamut at Lv. 100, it&amp;rsquo;s now more important to align with with raid buffs. SpS is also weaker at the beginning of the expansion, as a suitable amount of SpS to make the build remotely viable isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to get natively.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/openers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 07:52:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/openers/</guid><description>Openers Lv. 100 General Opener The below opener is the general go to opener for summoner and uses Titan as the first primal. Since the 6.1 changes, we can now use Searing Light in Bahamut, and choose to do so after the Bahamut GCD to avoid using a &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; GCD in our buff. You can choose to omit the precast Ruin III and use Bahamut at 0s as well. This may be an optimization strategy for particular fight timelines or encounters where the gained one second on cycle progression may matter.</description></item><item><title>Summoner Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 03:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/summoner/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome! This page is written to assist you throughout your leveling journey and provide insight on how the Summoner job will evolve from level one to level 100. Summoner may appear as a bit of a “unique” job with a lot of moving parts and multiple avenues of attacking enemies. Throughout this leveling guide, we will provide you with a basic fundamental understanding of each spell that you will unlock, as well as provide some quick rotation priorities and visualization examples.</description></item></channel></rss>