<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Red Mage on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/</link><description>Recent content in Red Mage on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 13:45:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Red Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 20:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 02:21:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Red Mage Skill Overview All skills are listed with their level 90 effects and potencies. Offensive On Global Cool Down Abilities Jolt II A 320 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases both Black and White Mana by 2. Verthunder III A 380 potency Spell with a cast time of five seconds that increases Black Mana by 6. Has a 50% chance to proc Verfire Ready. Verfire A 340 potency Spell with a cast time of two seconds that increases Black Mana by 5.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>6.X Red Mage Advanced Optimization Guide This guide will cover some Endwalker Red Mage optimization concepts and principles that aren’t fully covered in the basic job guide. The intended audience includes:
Red Mage players who have the fundamentals mostly down and are familiar with all the concepts in the basic job guide, but are trying to improve. High performing Red Mage players who get good logs through good GCD uptime, intuitive sense and repetition but wish to augment their theoretical understanding.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:35:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/faq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:35:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/openers/</guid><description>Full Size
Why do we cast Verthunder twice?
Casting Verthunder twice is intentional as it allows us to guarantee a proc from Verholy as we will have lower white mana when we use it, resulting in us having both procs after our melee combo. You can also do this in the reverse order, casting Veraero twice and then Verflare.
Why are we potting a GCD later than usual?
Potting after the 2nd GCD allows us to use both Swiftcast and Acceleration after the first GCD, beginning the cooldown of both of those abilities and allowing us to comfortably weave our potion, Manafication, and Embolden in the next 2 GCDs.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Red Mage Level 90 Guide for 6.x Overview This guide will cover proper rotations and ability usage in the Endwalker expansion. While the core foundation of Red Mage has not changed at all since its introduction in Stormblood, many smaller changes and quality of life improvements made in Endwalker have changed how we approach different aspects of the job.
At its simplest Red Mage has you casting spells to build your Black and White Mana to 50|50 and then spending that mana to use a melee combo with powerful finisher spells.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Red Mage Leveling Guide for 6.x Introduction The purpose of this guide is to assist players new to either Red Mage, or to the game entirely in learning how to properly play both their job and their role as they level up to 90. It will be split into sections for different level ranges that cover new abilities gained at these levels, as well as covering other basic concepts that will assist players in playing Red Mage.</description></item></channel></rss>