<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/</link><description>Recent content on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 03:23:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SCH TOP Fight Tips</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/scholar-top/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 03:23:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/scholar-top/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This document contains suggestions on how to use your cooldowns effectively and small things you can do to play each phase as effectively as possible. Ideally, you should communicate with your cohealer to make a plan that reduces stress for both of you and maximizes damage between you while being safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-omega-protocol-top">The Omega Protocol (TOP)&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="gearing">Gearing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TOP requires less mana than DSR so you can just use this &lt;a href="https://etro.gg/gearset/a91cf8ba-5ea1-4050-82c0-b90862a77ac0">2.40 set&lt;/a>. The benefits of 2.40 can come from good Chain/Aetherflow alignment and the ability to cast more broils during Pantokrator. That being said once you’re more comfortable with the first phase you will need to start holding at the end so as not to kill Omega too fast so the additional Broils will become more and more worthless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SCH DSR Fight Tips</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-dsr-fight-tips/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 03:14:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-dsr-fight-tips/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This document contains suggestions on how to use your cooldowns effectively and small things you can do to maximize them such as using Soil for two back-to-back damage instances that are just under 30s from each other. Ideally, you should communicate with your cohealer to make a plan that reduces stress for both of you and maximizes damage between you while being safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="dragonsong-reprise-dsr">Dragonsong Reprise (DSR)&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="gearing">Gearing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We have provided &lt;a href="https://xivgear.app/#/bis/sch/endwalker/dsr">multiple sets&lt;/a> based on your P7 Akh Morn strategy and heal plan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SCH UCOB fight tips</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-ucob-fight-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/scholar/fight-tips/sch-ucob-fight-tips/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This document contains suggestions on how to use your cooldowns effectively and small things you can do to maximize them. Ideally, you should communicate with your Co-Healer to make a plan that reduces stress for both of you and maximizes damage between you while being safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-unending-coil-of-bahamut-ucob">The Unending Coil of Bahamut (uCOB)&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="gearing">Gearing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For level 70 Ultimates and Healers, we can mostly get away with using all synced gear with at least ilevel 470. However, if you want to go out of your way to pick up some gear, Orator’s Mortarboard +2, Bonewicca Soother’s Chestpiece, Orator’s Shoes +2, and Bonewicca Ring of Healing are solid options when melded with Direct Hit. Reminder getting these pieces is not necessary and syncing gear down is a 4 DPS loss which truly does not matter.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>