<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machinist on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/machinist/</link><description>Recent content in Machinist on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 03:28:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/machinist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machinist Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 03:28:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single-Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heated Split Shot HS1 54 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 220. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Split Shot. Heated Slug Shot HS2 60 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 320. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Slug Shot. Heated Clean Shot HS3 64 Weaponskill 2.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Machinist Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 21:52:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Machinist Guide Welcome to the Basic Machinist Guide! Within this document, you&amp;rsquo;ll find all the information you&amp;rsquo;ll need to play the job well. The links below can be used as teleports to other pages if you need the information while learning the job. Any questions can be directed to the Machinist channels in our Discord.
Openers
Advanced Guide
Video Guide
Gearing and Meld Priority
Skills Overview
Frequently Asked Questions</description></item><item><title>Machinist Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</guid><description>Openers With the addition of the extra tools, and despite the fact that we want to optimize as best as we can into buffs, it is still ideal to start off with a prepull Reassemble. It shaves off quite a bit of time to get the cooldown rolling and could possibly net us an extra usage depending on the fight layout in Dawntrail. Depending on the fight, we can transpose Drill and Air Anchor in the opener if we can gain an extra Drill for it.</description></item><item><title>Machinist Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This guide is intended to give the reader the tools needed to approach encounter optimization as a Machinist. It assumes you are already familiar with the fundamentals of the job – if you need a refresher, please read the Basic Guide and come back when you&amp;rsquo;re done.
Introduction to Optimization This section will introduce some core concepts for optimizing encounters in FFXIV. If you are already familiar with optimization on other jobs, you can feel free to skip ahead!</description></item></channel></rss>