<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monk on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/</link><description>Recent content in Monk on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 01:46:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monk Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 01:46:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single Target GCDs Monk has six core single-target GCDs:
Dragon Kick has a potency of 320. When in Opo-Opo form, it will grant Opo-opo&amp;rsquo;s Fury. Bootshine has a potency of 220, or 420 when you have Opo-opo&amp;rsquo;s Fury. When in Opo-Opo form, Bootshine will always crit. Leaping Opo is the upgraded version of Bootshine, it has a potency of 260, or 460 when you have Opo-opo&amp;rsquo;s Fury. When in Opo-Opo form, Leaping Opo will always crit.</description></item><item><title>Monk Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 03:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Advanced Monk - Out of the Ballpit You have made it out of the ballpit and you know about the standard Monk rotation, as well as its Openers and Burst Windows. In the following section we will introduce knowledge that will help answer some questions about why the standard rotation is standard, and in more advanced fashion, why other considerations are not standard. As well as basic understanding of game mechanics, spreadsheet territory targeting single digit gains and in traditional fashion, cursed knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Monk Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Monk Guide Welcome to the basic guide for Monk, which will cover all of the information necessary to get you off your feet and onto your hands. Included is a look into the various systems that come together to define the Monk playstyle, suggested openers, and explanations on how to correctly form burst windows.
Throughout this guide we will be referring to all skills as if you were level 100.</description></item><item><title>Monk Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:59:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Know Your Role Melee DPS jobs have a unique mechanic in positionals. Certain actions will deal more damage when executed from the rear or flank of a target. Targets with continuous Target Rings will always take the increased damage from positional actions. The Role Action True North allows you to disregard positional requirements for ten seconds per use.
While it is a loss to miss your Positionals, landing them should be your last priority, after you have met all of the other combat priority requirements of a melee DPS job.</description></item><item><title>Monk Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 01:09:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Monk Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:33:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Monk FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:29:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</guid><description>Is Double True Strike dead?
As purely the best option, yup, go back to 1:1 Twin Snakes and True.
What&amp;rsquo;s with the double Dragon Kick in the openers?
With Standard, you DK after Perfect Balance for DK&amp;rsquo;s higher potency and again later to gain Leaden finally. With Early Buff a stanceless Leaden Boot after PB is worse on average than using the DK to guarantee a crit one.
What do non opener RoF windows look like?</description></item><item><title>Monk Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</guid><description>Openers &amp;ldquo;Which opener do I pick?&amp;rdquo; It depends on when your group is bursting. 5/7s don&amp;rsquo;t have any major implications one way or the other for us, so do what fits your party the best.
The choice between demo opener and dk opener will likely depend on your group’s buff timings or fight phasing: choose dk opener as the default.
As always, the choice between double lunar and solar lunar depends on your killtime.</description></item><item><title>Monk Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 23:27:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>