<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monk on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/</link><description>Recent content in Monk on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 23:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monk Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 23:27:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/best-in-slot/</guid><description>What do I meld on gear generally? Critical Hit, then Direct Hit and Determination
The BiS skill speed is at the 761 speed tier, for reference for skill speed.
What&amp;rsquo;s the BiS? Etro link (802 Speed):
https://etro.gg/gearset/388e7ee7-2919-49bf-b1d8-75fcfae73ce5
If you have a Relic you have this marginally better list of gear (etro&amp;rsquo;d courtesy of StormGail):
https://etro.gg/gearset/2a0fbde0-fa6f-47b6-aa0d-9b7d240c6e19 ­
SkS Tiers/Substat Tiers http://theoryjerks.akhmorning.com/stats/
Use these tables of on this website if you want to see how close you are to reaching your next stat breakpoint or just to further understand your stats in general.</description></item><item><title>Monk Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Monk Guide Welcome to the basic guide for Monk, which will cover all of the information necessary to get you off your feet and onto your hands while you kick some voidsent in the face. Included is a look into the various systems that come together to define the Monk playstyle, suggested openers, and explanations on how to correctly form burst windows. If your thirst for knowledge remains unsated once you reach the conclusion of this guide, head on over to the Advanced guide where we will dive further into the depths of forbidden Monk information.</description></item><item><title>Monk Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single Target GCDs Monk has six core single-target GCDs:
Bootshine has a potency of 210, or 310 when you have Leaden Fist. When in Opo-Opo form, Bootshine will always crit. Dragon Kick has a potency of 320. When in Opo-Opo form, it will grant the Leaden Fist buff. True Strike has a potency of 300. It can only be executed from Raptor form. Twin Snakes has a potency of 280. It also grants a 15% damage increase buff, Disciplined Fist, that lasts for 15 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Monk Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 14:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Advanced Monk Gameplay Techniques: Reaching Enlightenment Opener Variations The two basic opener choices are not going to work perfectly in every situation. As such, we can modify our openers quite easily in order to better suit our needs.
Early Openers An early opener is exactly what it sounds like. By skipping past the Opo GCD straight into a Twin Snakes, we are able to get our buffs on cooldown sooner. These openers are generally used in situations where a phase or fight would end while we are still in a buff window in order to squeeze more effective usage out of those buffs.</description></item><item><title>Monk Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 14:15:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/openers/</guid><description>Openers Other Resources Rotation Looping rotation - French translation - Korean translation - Other Resources Videos:
Comprehensive Monk Video Guide Braindead Looping 6:30 dummy rotation Optimal Drift 6:30 dummy rotation Double Solar 6:30 dummy rotation 6:30 Double Solar dummy + explanation (French)</description></item><item><title>Monk Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 08:04:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Monk Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:05:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Know Your Role Melee DPS jobs have a unique mechanic in positionals. Certain actions will deal more damage when executed from the rear or flank of a target. Targets with continuous Target Rings will always take the increased damage from positional actions. The Role Action True North allows you to disregard positional requirements for ten seconds per use.
While it is a loss to miss your Positionals, landing them should be your last priority, after you have met all of the other combat priority requirements of a melee DPS job.</description></item><item><title>Monk Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Monk FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:17:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/monk/faq/</guid><description>Is Double True Strike dead?
As purely the best option, yup, go back to 1:1 Twin Snakes and True.
What&amp;rsquo;s with the double Dragon Kick in the openers?
With Standard, you DK after Perfect Balance for DK&amp;rsquo;s higher potency and again later to gain Leaden finally. With Early Buff a stanceless Leaden Boot after PB is worse on average than using the DK to guarantee a crit one.
What do non opener RoF windows look like?</description></item></channel></rss>