<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>White Mage on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/</link><description>Recent content in White Mage on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 23:57:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>White Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 23:57:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>White Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 23:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>Introduction This guide aims to provide a basic overview of White Mage and offer guidelines on how to use each skill in its toolkit effectively in any environment. As healers do not have a strict healing rotation, this guide will focus on highlighting what makes each skill unique and explain some common use cases.
White Mage is considered by many people to be the most beginner friendly healer, and rightfully so.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>White Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description>In general this will boil down to choosing max item level gear with sufficient Piety while maximizing Crit, then melding Crit &amp;gt; DH/DET where possible, though Piety melds can be useful in a pinch if you end up too low.
Piety is a binary stat, as any more than you needed to not run out of mp was wasted stats. Because of this, when choosing our substats, avoiding excess Piety is the best way for us to increase our damage, and you&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes see our low piety sets use lower iLvl equipment to avoid Piety (this is still the exception rather than the rule, don&amp;rsquo;t actively use lower iLvl items to dodge Piety without calculating out the gain yourself).</description></item><item><title>White Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:35:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Oops, we don&amp;rsquo;t have that guide yet! Interested in contributing? Feel free to join the Balance Discord server to contact a job mentor/admin and express your interest!</description></item><item><title>White Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/openers/</guid><description>Standard Opener In most cases, use this:
-3s Pre-pull Current Tincture of Mind
-1.5s Pre-pull Glare III
PULL
Dia
Glare III
Glare III Weave: Presence of Mind
Glare III Weave: Assize Glare III (etc.)
This opener uses both PoM and Assize under raid buffs, Assize is weaved under PoM which can cause clipping even at moderate ping, in most cases this will not be an issue.
(To view the image full size click here.</description></item><item><title>White Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 16:33:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Gear and Job Quests Keep up to date with job quests; job quests will give you solid spells or vital gear. Make sure your gear has mind stat on it. You should always aim to keep your gear up to date, roll for dungeon gear with mind, and spend your tomestones on tomestone gear to equip it when you hit 50, 60, 70, and 80. You can find the vendors in Mor Dhona (50), Idyllshire (60), Rhalgr&amp;rsquo;s Reach (70), and Eulmore (80).</description></item><item><title>White Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Notable Endwalker Changes Thin Air has two charges but only reduces mana cost on one spell per cast. Glare cast time reduced to 1.5s. Presence of Mind changes to a 120s cooldown. Damage GCD Glare III Single target damage (310), 1.5 cast time At lower levels you&amp;rsquo;ll have Stone, which gets replaced by Glare at level 72 Can weave one oGCD after it Cast this when you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything else.</description></item><item><title>White Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 04:43:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/healers/white-mage/faq/</guid><description>White Mage FAQ How should movement and weaving be handled? White Mage (WHM) is one of the least mobile jobs in the game, and so planning movement is critical to success. Below is a list of available options; keep in mind that it’s heavily subjective based on the encounter and your party.
Pre-position with slidecasts and natural Dia refreshes Natural Dia refresh (&amp;lt; ~3s remaining), slidecast, or Swiftcast + Glare (not clipped, always consider holding for raise in prog) Rapture that does useful healing, Misery Regen that does necessary healing (rare in Savage and below) Overheal Lilies Dia outside natural refresh (almost always avoidable) Extended movements involve a combination of these roughly in order of priority, and a lot of movement can be minimized with proper prepositioning utilizing a combination of Dia and slidecasting.</description></item></channel></rss>