<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opener on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/opener/</link><description>Recent content in Opener on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/opener/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/tanks/paladin/basic-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Basics Guide for Paladin! Whether you are a fresh level 100, a returning player, or just need a refresher, this guide will get you started and allow you to hit the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is a basic introduction to level 100 Paladin, this guide will not go into many nuances and topics that are tied to high-end optimization. If you are looking for such information, you may find it in one of the dedicated guides below, or in discussion channels on the Balance discord:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/openers/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="graphics-and-notes"&gt;Graphics and Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class="md__image"&gt;
 &lt;img id="[22 327 187 147 446 155]" src="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/img/jobs/mch/machinist-standard-opener-aa-6-.png" onclick="openModal(this.id)" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
With the addition of the extra tools, and despite the fact that we want to optimize as best as we can into buffs, it is still ideal to start off with a prepull Reassemble. It shaves off quite a bit of time to get the cooldown rolling and could possibly net us an extra usage depending on the fight layout in Dawntrail. Depending on the fight, we can transpose Drill and Air Anchor in the opener if we can gain an extra Drill for it. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For now, Air Anchor remains the priority due to the huge value of 20 battery compared to the relatively small direct potency gain of using a tool over a combo GCD. The order of the oGCDs isn’t super important - we want to place the 2nd Reassemble in buffs, so it can be used on Excavator, or the following Drill, as long as it catches buffs. We want Wildfire to be used as early as possible within the buff window, so we weave it before Full Metal Field . We also aim to fit as many Double Check/Checkmate into buffs as possible. While we would much prefer a 2 minute pot if possible, some fights do not allow for this. If we have to use an opener pot, we want to use it two seconds before pulling the boss.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class="md__image"&gt;
 &lt;img id="[98 309 251 355 286 454]" src="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/img/jobs/mch/machinist-alternative-opener-static-to-even-minute-bursts-.png" onclick="openModal(this.id)" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>