<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bard on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/</link><description>Recent content in Bard on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 02:25:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bard Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 02:25:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/best-in-slot/</guid><description>5.5x Best In Slot BiS with Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/8418d22e-d70e-4b1a-87e0-d2b79dc3bd91
BiS, no Relic: https://etro.gg/gearset/865fc886-994f-4c28-8fc1-4379f160a916
2.50 BiS for high ping (relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/6e8892d6-68b0-4597-ba17-1efdc0e62084
2.50s BiS for high ping (no relic): https://etro.gg/gearset/cac58997-d0d5-4e92-b6fd-a131e8a775e2
TEA Best In Slot: Relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/1081f33f-8c37-4ef4-b569-30e30092174f
Relic 2.47s: https://etro.gg/gearset/f0eafbaf-fb74-48ee-99a8-21780ff8a793
(These are basically equal, pick to taste.)
No-relic 2.44s: https://etro.gg/gearset/c4e0a8ce-e69e-4efc-8971-f4ae5d4c5918
For level 70 Ultimates: Any gear that&amp;rsquo;s i470 or higher will suffice, as it syncs down to maximum substats for UWU. You can get some bonus value out of a 515/535 relic by keeping its substats at 318/280 or less (for UWU/UCoB).</description></item><item><title>Bard Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 03:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Bard Leveling Guide Gear Always use the gear with the highest dexterity available to you. This is more important than any secondary stat - you should not worry about those until endgame.
Aside from some early quest rewards and vendor gear bought for gil, a piece&amp;rsquo;s item level correlates to its Dexterity. So you can just use the highest item level gear and you&amp;rsquo;ll be good to go.
Bards use &amp;ldquo;Aiming&amp;rdquo; gear, so if you see that label on a coffer quest reward, that one is for you.</description></item><item><title>Bard Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/skills-overview/</guid><description>Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find notes and clarifications about Bard&amp;rsquo;s skills. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for tooltips, check the official website.
GCDs (share a Global Cooldown) Burst Shot (BS) Your go-to filler GCD on single targets. Use Burst Shot when you have no other GCDs you need to press. Refulgent Arrow (RA) Refulgent Arrow is usable when you have the not so aptly-named &amp;ldquo;Straight Shot Ready&amp;rdquo; buff. You can get this buff by using Burst Shot, Stormbite, Caustic Bite, Iron Jaws, or Barrage.</description></item><item><title>Bard Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/basic-guide/</guid><description>Welcome to the Basics Guide for Bard! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a fresh level 90, a returning player, or just need a refresher, this guide will get you started and help you feel comfortable.
This is a basic introduction to level 90 Bard. It will not go into many nuances, optimizations, or topics outside of playing the job in battle.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for such information, you may find it in one of the dedicated guides below:</description></item><item><title>Bard Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 22:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/advanced-guide/</guid><description>Hello! In this guide, you will find a series of details and optimizations for Endwalker Bard.
This builds on the Bard Basic Guide and expects you to be familiar with Bard&amp;rsquo;s skills, general priorities, opener, and song cycle.
Topics are ordered based on some mix of importance and flow. It is a little all over the place, but such is the nature of a kit like Bard&amp;rsquo;s.
The two-minute burst Like many jobs, Bard&amp;rsquo;s kit revolves around a big damage burst every two minutes, alongside a powerful duo of party-wide buffs, Battle Voice and Radiant Finale.</description></item><item><title>Bard FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 04:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/faq/</guid><description>Single target FAQ When should I use Raging Strikes after the opener?
A couple of GCDs into Minuet. This is to cover as much Pitch Perfect potential as possible.
When do I use my second/third potion?
Try to cover Raging Strikes and Barrage with it. That damage spike is bigger than any heap of party buffs. If you can, also try to pop it right before an Iron Jaws, so that you can IJ at the end and get two runs of buffed DoTs.</description></item><item><title>Bard Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 22:51:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bard Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/bard/openers/</guid><description>Bard Openers For all openers:
Use Pitch Perfect at three stacks as able, Bloodletter as able, and Refulgent procs as you get them. Hold Barrage until the next GCD if you already have an Refulgent proc. The best potion as of 6.00 is high-quality Grade 5 Tincture of Dexterity. Opener FAQ Is it really okay to use Radiant Finale for only 2% in the opener?
Yes, by the next two-minute burst you will have gotten three more coda.</description></item></channel></rss>