<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guides on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Becoming A Better Tank</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/becoming-a-better-tank/</guid><description>Version 1.0 Torael Valdis | Jenova (NA) | Torael_Valdis#8120
This guide is written with the intention to be hosted on The Balance Discord and should not be hosted elsewhere without consent of the owner.
Table of Contents Introduction
Mindset
Mitigation
Mitigating As The Off Tank Facilitating Party Uptime
Damage
Consistency and Adaptability
Closing Thoughts
Special Thanks Changelog Intro “What is Tanking: Tanking in Final Fantasy 14, in the most basic of ideas, is controlling the Enmity of the enemies and reducing the damage you take from said enemies.</description></item><item><title>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/endgame-gearing-and-content-unlock-guide/</guid><description>Endgame Gearing and Content Unlock Guide
Introduction This is a comprehensive guide aimed towards players entering endgame — Level 90 — for the first time and getting overwhelmed with Final Fantasy XIV&amp;rsquo;s gear progression systems. This guide will help you get an understanding of how FFXIV’s endgame systems work, as well as how to gear up and what types of endgame PvE content exist.
Step 1. Get AF gear, finish MSQ, and farm Tomestones for gear.</description></item><item><title>Guide to Leveling Reaper and Sage Immediately in Endwalker</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/guide-to-leveling-reaper-and-sage-immediately-in-endwalker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/guide-to-leveling-reaper-and-sage-immediately-in-endwalker/</guid><description>Written by: Ringabel Dim (DNC Mentor in The Balance)
On November 19th - Early Access of Endwalker, many players may be interested in leveling either Reaper or Sage as their first job in the new expansion. This guide provides info on what to prepare and how to optimize your time to level from 70 to 80 as quick as possible.
EXP Sources to Prepare Before Endwalker is Released: Wondrous Tails (roughly 50%): Pick up Wondrous Tails in Idyllshire on the week of Tuesday, November 9th.</description></item><item><title>Tanking FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-faq/</guid><description>Tanking FAQ What Food / Potion do tanks use? Grade 4 Tincture of Strength Chicken Fettuccine OR Smoked Chicken What do I meld? Read the &amp;ldquo;Stats&amp;rdquo; section
Why is my combo breaking? The combo timer is exactly 15 seconds long. This means that you can do the following:
Combo 1 Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Spender GCD Combo 2 As long as the time between the cast of Combo 1 and Combo 2 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exceed 15s.</description></item><item><title>Tanking Stats and Materia</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/tanking-stats-and-materia/</guid><description>Tanking Stats and Materia Stats Stat Priority Weapon Damage Main stat (Str/Vit on tanks) Substats There are no &amp;ldquo;Stat weights&amp;rdquo;.
Weapon Damage almost always comes with main stat increase.
Higher item level almost always comes with main stat increase.
Upgrade your gear as often as possible
Skill Speed (at level 80) 2.43s GCD - 1015 SkS 2.42s GCD - 1117 SkS 2.41s GCD - 1218 SkS 2.40s GCD - 1320 SkS 2.</description></item><item><title>Zyrk's Bullshit Guide to the Principles of Healing</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/guide/zyrks-bullshit-guide-to-the-principles-of-healing/</guid><description>Zyrk’s FFXIV Shadowbringers Healing Guide Learn how to hate your party, the game, and yourself About the Author Hi, I’m Zyrkhan Dar’locke. My name is blue on The Balance, and that’s basically all I have to say for myself. You may also know me as “what?” and “literally who.” I’m here to talk about healing and stuff, because I guess I like it or something, mostly because I don’t respect myself.</description></item></channel></rss>