<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Black Mage on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/</link><description>Recent content in Black Mage on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 02:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Mage Best in Slot (BiS)</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 02:19:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/best-in-slot/</guid><description>BiS: &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS Tier (Relic)&amp;rdquo;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/1c64d9a9-892b-48a8-b7d1-f760839d659c
&amp;ldquo;Crit 2030 SPS Tier (Relic)&amp;rdquo;:
https://etro.gg/gearset/b470c4c6-6f4a-47c8-8162-52ac09494e02
&amp;ldquo;SMN/RDM-Friendly BiS&amp;rdquo;: (can use the SMN/RDM BiS without swapping melds)
Use the &amp;ldquo;Speed 3655 SpS&amp;rdquo; Tier set for BLM, and use SMN/RDM BiS on the other casters. Shared pieces between the sets have no meld conflicts.
Thanks to incoherent#0649 for the provided relic sets!
Please see http://bit.ly/BLMGear for additional sets, including non-relic BiS sets
&amp;ldquo;TEA BiS&amp;rdquo;: (Please look at the sheet below under &amp;ldquo;Patch 5.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Stat Priority</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 01:19:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/stat-priority/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black Mage Changes</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/job-changes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:58:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/job-changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Black Mage FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:52:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/faq/</guid><description>Q: What is Umbral Soul used for? A: Purely a downtime tool, a better version of Transpose. Lets you build back up to Umbral Ice III + Three Umbral Hearts during downtime, so you can Thunder III -&amp;gt; Fire III when you can hit something again. If you end a fight in Astral Fire, Transpose into UI so you can use Umbral Soul. Do not use Umbral Soul during uptime.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:47:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/skills-overview/</guid><description>Actions Icon Action Level Type MP Casting Recast Description Blizzard 1 Spell 400 2.5s 2.5s Deals ice damage with a potency of 180.
Additional Effect: Grants Umbral Ice or Removes Astral Fire.
Duration:15s. Fire 2 Spell 800 2.5s 2.5s Deals fire damage with a potency of 180.
Additional Effect: Grants Astral Fire or removes Umbral Ice
Duration: 15s
Additional Effect: 40% chance to grant Firestarter
Firestarter Effect: Next Fire III will cost no MP and have no cast time</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Openers</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:37:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/openers/</guid><description>Openers Openers should put abilities on cooldown, fit strong spells within buff windows, and minimize clipping. All openers assume there is a pull countdown and the boss is pulled at zero. If your group pulls earlier, adjust them as necessary. Use the highest tier Potion of Intelligence available.
Fire III Opener The standard opener for BLM. This opener has a rough bare minimum GCD (recast) of 2.45s, though most people will likely want some more Spell Speed than this for consistency in execution.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/basic-guide/</guid><description>7.x Black Mage Guide By: Rika Vanih
Job Overview Black Mage is a caster specializing in high, steady personal damage in place of providing party buffs. The job maintains a cyclical flow of expending MP via long, powerful casts in Astral Fire then swapping to refresh MP in Umbral Ice. While the rotation itself is somewhat simple, utilizing its movement tools and the flexibility built into its rotation to their fullest is key to maintaining uptime and maximizing damage as a Black Mage.</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 01:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/leveling-guide/</guid><description>Single Target Leveling Rotation Always keep your single-target Thunder on the target and only refresh it when it is about to fall off (less than three seconds), unless the target will die soon. This means that while you get a new Thunderhead buff each transition between Astral Fire and Umbral Ice, you will often end up ignoring/overwriting the buff until it is time to refresh the DoT.
Sub Level 35 Fire spam until low MP &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; Blizzard until max MP &amp;gt; Transpose &amp;gt; repeat</description></item><item><title>Black Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:24:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/black-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>While a lot of the higher-end optimization for BLM was removed with the release of Dawntrail, there are still some elements of nuance and optimization that will be covered in an Advanced Guide in the future. For now, please refer to the main guide, notably the Additional Optimizations section for some preliminary concepts.</description></item></channel></rss>