<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guide on Balance Guides</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/guide/</link><description>Recent content in Guide on Balance Guides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:51:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reaper Basic Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:51:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/basic-guide/</guid><description>Basic Reaper Guide Welcome to the Basic Guide for Reaper, which will cover everything you need to know to get started with becoming a Reaper! Included are an overview of the job’s playstyle, basic priority, abilities and core concepts.
Whether you’re a fresh level 100, a returning player, or just need a refresh, this guide will give you the tools you need to feel comfortable playing Reaper.
This guide is intended to be relatively basic and doesn’t go into huge explanations of specific situations or small nuances.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Leveling Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:51:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/leveling-guide/</guid><description>This guide is targeted at players looking to play and understand Reaper as they level up. It will cover some basic priorities for each level tier and will also serve as a priority list for playing Reaper at lower levels (for ultimates and such). If you are level 100 and looking to explore other guides please visit the following links:
Basic Guide
Advanced Guide
Skill Details
How to Unlock To unlock Reaper, you must first have these prerequisites met:</description></item><item><title>Machinist Skills Overview</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 03:28:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/machinist/skills-overview/</guid><description>Single-Target Actions Icon Action Abbreviation Level Type Recast Description Heated Split Shot HS1 54 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The first skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a potency of 220. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Split Shot. Heated Slug Shot HS2 60 Weaponskill 2.5 seconds The second skill in your main combo. Delivers an attack with a combo potency of 320. Generates 5 Heat. Upgraded from Slug Shot. Heated Clean Shot HS3 64 Weaponskill 2.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 02:44:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/advanced-guide/</guid><description>This guide will be updated for Dawntrail at a later date.</description></item><item><title>Reaper Non-Standard Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/melee/reaper/non-standard/</guid><description>Placeholder Test page.</description></item><item><title>Red Mage Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 03:36:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/casters/red-mage/advanced-guide/</guid><description>6.X Red Mage Advanced Optimization Guide This guide will cover some Endwalker Red Mage optimization concepts and principles that aren’t fully covered in the basic job guide. The intended audience includes:
Red Mage players who have the fundamentals mostly down and are familiar with all the concepts in the basic job guide, but are trying to improve. High performing Red Mage players who get good logs through good GCD uptime, intuitive sense and repetition but wish to augment their theoretical understanding.</description></item><item><title>Dancer Advanced Guide</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 15:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/advanced-guide/</guid><description>by Io Whitespirit (Faerie)
FOREWORD One of the biggest requests I have had is a more concise document on what people “need to know” before jumping into more difficult content. This is not meant to be a replacement for a general guide to Dancer; please see Ringabel’s extensive write-up instead, which will be linked at the end of the document in the appendix.
This guide will be broken down into three sections: Basics, Intermediate, and Advanced.</description></item><item><title>Dancer FAQ</title><link>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.thebalanceffxiv.com/jobs/ranged/dancer/faq/</guid><description>DANCE PARTNER PRIORITY This list is made in a gear/skill vacuum. This is the recommended partner priority list.
Special Note: some fights may favor certain Dance Partners over others based on phases/mechanics or ability to hit multiple targets.
Updated: January 19, 2021 to account for balance changes in patch 5.4.
SAM NIN MNK / BLM (crit build)* DRG / SMN RDM MCH BRD DNC *Data on BLM SpS build as a dance partner is not available due to length in time to reach BiS with this build as of this update, but value as a dance partner is believed to drop significantly between the two builds due to under utilization of Devilment.</description></item></channel></rss>